[鳥鳴]
[birds chirping]
[自行車鈴響]
[bicycle bell dings]
-哦！ -看它！
-Oh! -Watch it!
怎麼了，埃迪？
What's it to be, Eddie?
好消息還是壞消息？
Good news or bad?
哦！ [輕笑]
Oh! [chuckles]
哦。
Oh.
-早安，錢德勒。 - 早上好，哈里斯夫人。
-Morning, Chandler. -Good morning, Mrs. Harris.
-你好嗎？ - 今天是我的幸運日。
-How are you? -It's my lucky day today.
- 每天都一樣。 -[輕笑]
-Same as every day. -[chuckles]
謝謝你。
Thank you.
好的。
All right.
為什麼沒有人坐那個位子？
Why's no one took that seat?
- 也許我為你保存它。 -[輕笑]
-Maybe I saving it for you. -[chuckles]
那就推過去吧。
Shove over, then.
[嘆氣]
[sighs]
你不會相信的，維。
You won't believe this, Vi.
最奇怪的事情剛剛發生。
The strangest thing's just happened.
我認為這是一個跡象。
I reckon it's a sign.
艾達哈里斯，為什麼你的那個人
Ada Harris, why that man of yours
不能像其他人一樣使用帖子？
can't use the post like everybody else?
不是一個作家，我的埃迪。
Not much of a writer, my Eddie.
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
六：哦！好冷。
VI: Ooh! So cold.
-有人來嗎？ -不。
-Anyone coming? -No.
-不？ -全清。
-No? -All clear.
[安靜的喋喋不休]
[quiet chatter]
-[笑聲] -哦，早上好，紐康先生。
-[laughter] -Oh, morning, Mr. Newcombe.
早早起來。
Up bright and early.
值班電話，哈里斯夫人。
Duty calls, Mrs. Harris.
呃，我的侄女，波西亞。
Uh, my niece, Portia.
哦，很高興，我敢肯定。
Oh, delighted, I'm sure.
-早晨。 -早晨。
-Morning. -Morning.
[單曲]：噢噢噢，彭羅斯小姐。
[singsongy]: Ooh-ooh, Miss Penrose.
[重重地呼出一口氣]
[exhales heavily]
[嘲笑]
[scoffs]
彈開。
Bombs away.
你不是很早嗎？
Aren't you awfully early?
1:00 半過去了，親愛的。
It's gone half past 1:00, dear.
不。
No.
天哪，我該死的試鏡。
Christ, my bloody audition.
[呻吟]
[groans]
哦，我沒衣服穿。
Oh, I haven't a thing to wear.
哦，你穿什麼都很可愛，親愛的。
Oh, you look lovely in anything, dear.
那裡。
There.
那這個呢？
What about this?
哦，你對我的……腳本做了什麼？
Oh, what have you done with my... script?
哦，等一下，等一下。不掛斷。
Oh, hang on, hang on. Hang on.
哦，看在上帝的份上。
Oh, for God's sake.
那裡。祝你好運，親愛的。
There. Good luck, sweetheart.
謝謝，親愛的。
Thanks, darling.
你是天使。
You're an angel.
沒有你我該怎麼辦？
What would I do without you?
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
-[熱鬧的喋喋不休] -[音樂播放]
-[lively chatter] -[music playing]
VI：讓我們盡情享受吧！
VI: Let's enjoy ourselves!
[笑]
[laughs]
[Chuck Berry 演奏的“Johnny B. Goode”]
["Johnny B. Goode" by Chuck Berry playing]
在路易斯安那州的深處，靠近新奧爾良......
Deep down in Louisiana close to New Orleans...
好吧，如果不是了不起的H夫人
Well, if it isn't the marvelous Mrs. H
和她可信賴的伙伴。
and her trusty sidekick.
女士們，我能給你什麼？這是幸運的一周。
What can I get you, ladies? It's been a lucky week.
-哦。 - 兩個港口和檸檬。
-Oh. -Two port and lemon.
如果您是博彩公司，每週都很幸運。
Every week's lucky if you're the bookmaker.
你沒有錯，親愛的。
You're not wrong there, love.
請給我兩份波特酒和檸檬。
Two port and lemon, please.
當然，現在我有你的公司，我在三葉草。
Course, now I've got your company, I'm in clover.
阿奇先生，你以為只要喝一杯就能得到我們的陪伴？
You think you get our company for one drink, Mr. Archie?
現在，這兩個是對性格的正確判斷。
Now, these two are a proper judge of character.
他們喜歡你，艾達哈里斯。
They like you, Ada Harris.
如果他們這麼聰明，他們為什麼要和你在一起？
Why they stick with you, if they're so smart?
你為什麼要和她在一起，她那麼暴躁？
Why do you stick with her, her so crabby?
我第一次輪班建造飛機時遇到了她。
Met her me first shift building planes.
從來沒有更好的朋友。
Never had a better friend.
這個麻煩，她總是說真話。
Trouble with this one, she always speak the truth.
-[輕笑] -忍不住。
-[chuckles softly] -Can't help herself.
那是一種可怕的痛苦。
That is a terrible affliction.
好吧，請自重，女士們。
All right, behave yourself, ladies.
我會監督你的。
I'll be watching you.
[歡快的音樂播放]
[upbeat music playing]
戰爭已經很久了。
War's been over a long time.
你的埃迪永遠不會回來了。
Your Eddie's never coming back.
繼續。
Go on.
[林肯理由/帕特雷福德的“小石頭”]
["Little Bit of Rock" by Lincoln Grounds/Pat Reyford]
是的。
Yeah.
我有一個女孩，她看起來很好
I got a gal, she looks just fine
總是給我帶來威士忌和葡萄酒
Always bring me whiskey and wine
早上吃早餐，晚上吃晚餐
Breakfast in the morning and dinner at night
她所做的一切，她都做得恰到好處
Everything she do, she do just right
當我說，“你想做什麼？”
And when I say, "What you wanna do?"
她說：“我只想從你這裡得到一件事”
She said, "There's just one thing that I want from you"
一點搖滾，一點搖滾
A little bit of rock, a little bit of roll
一點石頭
A little bit of rock
[褪色]：哦，有點滾動......
[fading]: Ooh, a little bit of roll...
VI：“親愛的哈里斯夫人，
VI: "Dear Mrs. Harris,
“請找到隨附的個人物品
"Please find enclosed the personal effects
“愛德華·哈里斯中士，
"of Sergeant Edward Harris,
“從波蘭華沙附近的墜機現場找到。
"recovered from a crash site near Warsaw, Poland.
“由於這一發現，
"As a result of this discovery,
“哈里斯中士現在被派去……
"Sergeant Harris is now posted...
“在行動中喪生，
"killed in action,
“1944 年 3 月 2 日。
"2 March 1944.
“請等待進一步的溝通
"Please await further communication
來自英國皇家空軍中央管理局。”
from RAF Central Administration."
哦，艾達。
Oh, Ada.
我很抱歉。
I'm so sorry.
我、我應該知道他...
I-I should've known he...
如果他可以的話，他會回到我身邊的，你知道...
He would've got back to me if he could've, you know...
不管怎樣。
one way or another.
出色地...
Well...
就是這樣。
that's that, then.
自由自在，不拘小節。
Footloose and fancy-free.
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
好吧，親愛的。
All right, love.
我希望它很快。
I hope it was quick.
想你。 [抽鼻子]
Miss you. [sniffles]
不，晚上做，絕對，
No, the evening do, absolutely,
但不是婚禮早餐。
but not the wedding breakfast.
嗯，你知道的，夫人……
Uh, you know, Mrs....
哈里斯夫人，對不起。你能不能...
Mrs. Harris, excuse me. Could you just...
就拿那個……[喃喃自語]
just take that... [mutters]
-不，那是敲詐勒索。 -哦。
-No, that is extortion. -Oh.
你必須回去向他們解釋
You must go back and explain to them
我們不可能負擔得起。
that we can't possibly afford that.
嗯，當然必須是香檳。
Well, of course it must be champagne.
我-我-我...提醒他們查爾斯是他們的議員。
I-I-I... Remind them that Charles is their MP.
那一定是值得的，對吧？
That must be worth something, huh?
是的。 [輕笑]
Yes. [chuckles]
Toodle-pip。
Toodle-pip.
這場婚禮將是我的死亡。
This wedding's going to be the death of me.
你有孩子嗎，哈里斯夫人？
Do you have children, Mrs. Harris?
從頭到尾都是一場噩夢。
A nightmare of expense from start to finish.
哦是的。
Oh, yes.
可憐的老海軍上將丹特
Poor old Admiral Dant
不得不做出最後的犧牲。
had to make the ultimate sacrifice.
啟航前往佳士得和更溫暖的海岸。
Setting sail for Christie's and balmier shores.
可怕的男人，無論如何。
Dreadful man, by all accounts.
說到賬目，丹特夫人，
Talking of accounts, Lady Dant,
我想知道你是否可以設置...
I was wondering if you might be able to sett...
我們已經勒緊腰帶很久了，
We've been tightening our belts for so long now,
這是一個奇蹟，我們都還能呼吸。
it's a miracle we can all still breathe.
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
[嘆氣]
[sighs]
——丹特夫人：這不是神聖的嗎？ -哦。
-LADY DANT: Isn't it divine? -Oh.
我發誓我永遠不會踏上蒙田大道，
I swore I would never set foot in the Avenue Montaigne,
但是婚禮和“在巴黎的時候”和...
but what with the wedding and "when in Paris" and...
在我看到拉維桑特的那一刻...
The moment I laid eyes on Ravissante...
-[耳語]：拉維桑特。 -...我被迷住了。
-[whispers]: Ravissante. -...I was ravished.
達到500磅。
To the tune of 500 pounds.
500塊錢買一件衣服？
500 quid for a dress?
噓，噓，噓。丹特勳爵。
Shh, shh, shh. Lord Dant.
我不介意承認事情已經發生
I don't mind admitting things have been
最近有點血腥，但是...
a bit bloody of late, but...
當我穿上它...
when I put it on...
...別的都無所謂。
...nothing else matters.
[輕笑]
[chuckles softly]
丹特勳爵 [呼叫]：樂天？
LORD DANT [calling]: Lotte?
丹特夫人：現在，快，把它藏起來。
LADY DANT: Now, quickly, hide it away.
陛下一定看不到
His Lordship must not see it
直到我有時間為他工作。
until I've had time to work on him.
[顫抖]：哦。
[shuddering]: Oh.
[水龍頭吱吱聲，停水]
[faucet squeaks, water stops]
[輕輕嘆氣]
[sighs softly]
拉維桑特。
Ravissante.
克里斯汀·迪奧。
By Christian Dior.
[紙張沙沙作響]
[paper rustles]
晚上愛。
Night, love.
南倫敦郵報！
South London Post!
週六結果！
Saturday results!
你所有的足球成績。
All your football results.
-哦！ - 南倫敦郵報！
-Oh! -South London Post!
-對不起。 - 週六結果！
-Sorry. -Saturday results!
你所有的足球成績。
All your football results.
- 南倫敦郵報！ -[嘆氣]
-South London Post! -[sighs]
週六結果！
Saturday results!
播音員[通過無線電]：曼聯二，
ANNOUNCER [over radio]: Manchester United two,
布萊克浦二。
Blackpool two.
紐卡斯爾五，
Newcastle five,
利物浦三。
Liverpool three.
普雷斯頓北端二，
Preston North End two,
朴茨茅斯二。
Portsmouth two.
現在我們回到體育報導的其餘部分。
And now we return to the rest of the sports report.
[收音機播放管弦樂]
[orchestral music playing over radio]
[維呻吟]
[Vi groans]
[維嘆氣]
[Vi sighs]
不！不！
No! No!
哦，這是我的埃迪。
Oh, it's my Eddie.
是我的天使。
It's my angel.
你對我太單純了，女人？
You gone simple on me, woman?
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
[笑]：我贏了，Vi。
[laughing]: I won, Vi.
我贏了。
I've won.
[都笑了]
[both laughing]
[有節奏的叮噹聲]
[rhythmic clanging]
[哇，大笑]
[whooping, laughing]
-[重擊] -[男人模糊地喊叫]
-[thumping] -[man shouts indistinctly]
你想對她好。
You want to make nice to her.
她只是走了並贏得了游泳池。
She's only gone and won the pools.
[笑]
[laughing]
艾達，你要做什麼？
Ada, what you going to do?
[喘氣]：我要去買件衣服。
[panting]: I'm going to buy a dress.
軍團之舞的東西很漂亮。
Something pretty for the Legion Dance.
-是的。 -[維笑]
-Yeah. -[Vi laughing]
來自巴黎的 Christian Dior 連衣裙。
A Christian Dior dress from Paris.
500 英鎊。
500 quid.
[都笑了]
[both laughing]
你贏了多少？
How much you win?
[嘎嘎]
[rattling]
錢德勒：還有票嗎？
CHANDLER: Any more tickets, please?
去哪兒，女士？
Where to, ma'am?
單身，紫小姐？
Single, Miss Violet?
嗯嗯。沒有人為我清理之後。
Mm-hmm. No cleaning up after no man for me.
[錢德勒笑聲]
[Chandler chuckling]
-啊。 -早上好，紐科姆先生。
-Ah. -Morning, Mr. Newcombe.
哈里斯夫人，我，呃……
Mrs. Harris, I, uh...
我不相信你見過我的侄女薩曼莎。
I don't believe you've met my niece, Samantha.
哦，不，我沒有享受過。
Oh, no, I haven't had the pleasure.
嗯，紐康先生。
Um, Mr. Newcombe.
如果你知道有誰可以使用我的服務——嗯...
If you know of anyone who could use me services-- um...
也許是你的一個侄女？
one of your nieces, perhaps?
薩曼莎，H夫人是謹慎的靈魂。
Samantha, Mrs. H is the soul of discretion.
如果不是我旋鈕上的拋光劑，人們永遠不會知道她曾經去過。
One would never know she'd been but for the polish on my knobs.
哦，賈爾斯。
Oh, Giles.
-[賈爾斯輕笑]-[嘆氣]
-[Giles chuckling] -[sighs]
[猛烈地吹]
[blows sharply]
[Juliette Gr 的《On n'oublie rien》？共演奏]
["On n'oublie rien" by Juliette Gr?韶co playing]
[歌曲繼續用法語唱歌]
[song continues with singing in French]
[一起哼唱]
[humming along]
謝謝你。
Thank you.
[模糊的喋喋不休]
[indistinct chatter]
[歌曲繼續用法語唱歌]
[song continues with singing in French]
-[相機快照] -[急促地呼氣]
-[camera snaps] -[exhales sharply]
哦。 [輕笑]
Oh. [chuckles]
[相機快照]
[camera snaps]
[歌曲結束]
[song ends]
對不起試鏡，親愛的。
Sorry about the audition, love.
哦，我不知道我為什麼要打擾。
Oh, I don't know why I bother.
“太年輕。” “太老。”
"Too young." "Too old."
“太高了。” “太胖。”
"Too tall." "Too fat."
你是對的，鴨子。
You're just right, ducks.
我二十……三歲。
I'm twenty... three.
再過幾年，對我來說一切都結束了。
Couple more years, and it's all over for me.
哦，你有足夠的時間。
Oh, you've plenty of time.
你無法想像那是什麼樣的，哈里斯夫人，
You can't imagine what it's like, Mrs. Harris,
總是不得不擔心你的外表。
always having to worry about your looks.
VI：嘿，灰姑娘，你為什麼給他們帶來破布？
VI: Hey, Cinderella, why'd you bring them rags?
我要去參加舞會...
I will go to the ball...
當我給我穿衣服的時候。
when I get me dress.
哦，大寫的“A”帶來了麻煩。
Oh, here comes trouble with a capital "A."
你好，阿奇。
Hello, Archie.
-Ada，我所追求的那個女孩。 -[狗吠]
-Ada, the very girl I was after. -[dog barks]
-鴨子們，我能為你做什麼？ -現在，不要讓我興奮。
-What can I do for you, ducks? -Now, don't get me excited.
你知道我有一個狡猾的股票行情。
You know I've got a dodgy ticker.
[偷笑]：哦，放開你。
[chuckling]: Oh, get away with you.
她有比你更大的計劃。
She got bigger plans than you.
我理解了。
I can see that.
那麼，你介意幫我一個忙嗎
So, would you mind doing me a favor
並照顧春夏？
and look after Spring and Summer?
[輕笑]：因為 Cynthia 有
[chuckling]: Because Cynthia there's
不完全是狗最好的朋友。
not exactly a dog's best friend.
繼續。
Go on.
阿奇：謝謝。
ARCHIE: Thank you.
你是絕對的明星。
You are an absolute star.
你沒事。
And you're all right.
C？好的，我們開始吧。
C? All right, here we go.
搖搖尾巴，寶貝。
Shake that tail, baby.
這就是我們，Vi。
That's what we are, Vi.
看不見的女人。
The invisible women.
為自己說話。
Speak for yourself.
[深吸一口氣]
[inhales deeply]
他們看到我來了。毫米！
They see me coming. Mm!
[都笑了]
[both laughing]
兩人：哦！
BOTH: Oh!
對不起，女士。
Beg your pardon, milady.
夫人，嗯，我的帳戶。
Milady, um, my account.
我想知道你是否可以安頓下來。
I was wondering if you might settle up.
哦，我很抱歉，哈里斯夫人。
Oh, I'm so sorry, Mrs. Harris.
恐怕我忘記去銀行了。
I'm afraid I forgot to pop to the bank.
這場婚禮是一場噩夢。
This wedding is a nightmare.
[笑]：每個人都說是的。
[chuckling]: Everybody has said yes.
哦，嗯...
Oh, um...
你不會介意等到下週吧？
you wouldn't mind waiting until next week, would you?
嗯，問題是，
Well, uh, the thing is,
它變得有點緊迫，因為我需要......
it's become a bit pressing because I need to...
哦，是時候了嗎？ [嘲笑，嘆息]
Oh, is that the time? [scoffs, sighs]
實際上，哈里斯夫人，
Actually, Mrs. Harris,
恐怕我將不得不減少你的工作時間。
I'm afraid I'm going to have to reduce your hours.
減少？ N-不，請。小姐，請...
Reduce? N-No, please. Milady, please...
好吧，這些天我們都必須節省開支，不是嗎？
Well, we all have to economize these days, don't we?
對不起。
Sorry.
[雷聲隆隆]
[thunder rumbling]
[附近有狗叫]
[dog barking nearby]
【遠處的腳步聲】
[footsteps in distance]
[敲門聲]
[knocking]
VI：我知道你在那裡，女人，在黑暗和寒冷中。
VI: I know you're there, woman, in the dark and cold.
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
我沒事，維。
I'm all right, Vi.
[維嘆氣]
[Vi sighs]
阿奇讓我們自由進入白城。
Archie has got us free into White City.
哦，不，我已經把這一切都修好了。
Oh, no, I've got all this mending.
-啊-啊-啊-啊-啊-啊-啊-啊。 -N-沒有。不，不，維。
-Ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah. -N-No. No, no, Vi.
六...哦。
Vi... Oh.
VI：讓我們開心一點。
VI: Have us a bit of fun.
-[鈴聲響起] -[人群歡呼]
-[bell rings] -[crowd cheering]
-[模糊的喋喋不休] -[Vi 輕笑]
-[indistinct chatter] -[Vi chuckling]
[關於 P.A. 的模糊公告]
[indistinct announcement over P.A.]
ADA：哦，天哪。看。
ADA: Oh, good Lord. Look.
這是一個標誌。
It's a sign.
你有好的秘訣嗎？
You got a good tip?
ADA [笑]：是的！
ADA [laughing]: Yeah!
-是的，我有！ -[笑]
-Yeah, I have! -[laughing]
-嗯...藉口...藉口... -ARCHIE [輕笑]：嘿。
-Um... excu... excuse... -ARCHIE [chuckling]: Hey.
-打擾一下。 -Ada，你喜歡顫抖嗎？
-Excuse me. -Ada, you fancy a flutter?
-是的。 -會是什麼？
-Yeah. -What'll it be?
六號100英鎊。
100 quid on number six.
要贏。
To win.
一噸？
A ton?
為了邁克的愛，艾達，不，把它收起來。
For the love of Mike, Ada, no, put it away.
不，第六號。
No. Number six.
- 高級時裝，請。 - 狗是一袋骨頭。
-Haute Couture, please. -The dog's a bag of bones.
它不能靠火箭取勝。
It couldn't win with a rocket up its arse.
你告訴她，阿奇。
You tell her, Archie.
她失去了她的大理石。
She's lost her marbles.
不，是高級時裝。
No, it's Haute Couture.
這是一個標誌。怎麼可能是別的？
It's a sign. How could it be anything else?
艾達，女孩，我已經做了很長時間了，好嗎？
Ada, girl, I've been doing this a long time, all right?
標誌不會贏得比賽。
Signs don't win races.
直到今晚，他們沒有。 [輕笑]
Not till tonight, they didn't. [chuckles]
我的錢很好。
My money's good.
請數一數。
Count it, please.
是的。 [笑]
Yeah. [laughs]
[關於 P.A. 的模糊公告]
[indistinct announcement over P.A.]
這裡。
Here.
開始了。那挺好的。
Here we go. That's good.
哦，我們找到了一個好地方。正確的。
Oh, we got a good spot. Right.
[吠叫]
[barks]
-哦。祝我好運。 -[笑]
-Oh. Wish me luck. -[laughs]
-哦，艾達。 -來吧，高級時裝。
-Oh, Ada. -Come on, Haute Couture.
[叮]
[dings]
[人群歡呼]
[crowd cheering]
[尖叫，笑聲]
[squeals, laughs]
-哦，看，她在領先！ -[Vi 喘息，大笑]
-Oh, look, she's in the lead! -[Vi gasps, laughs]
來吧！
Come on!
-[尖叫] -它在前面。
-[squeals] -It's in front.
來吧！ [喘氣]
Come on! [gasping]
-[人群呻吟] -[嗚咽]
-[crowd groaning] -[whimpers]
播音員：這是聰明的伯爵，
ANNOUNCER: It's Clever Count,
藍色條紋和暴風雨灣。
Blue Streak, and Stormy Bay.
你會看那個 - 高級時裝剛剛
And would you look at that-- Haute Couture has just
醒來，想起了她來這裡的目的。
woken up and remembered what she's here for.
[公告繼續模糊]
[announcement continues indistinctly]
嗯……[嘆氣]
Well... [sighs]
向你致敬，女孩。
Hats off to you, girl.
你去爭取了。
You went for it.
我會去找聖約翰救護車。
I'll go find a St John's Ambulance.
他們可能有很多白蘭地。
They might have a tot of brandy.
為了我。
For me.
你是對的，Vi——所有的錢。
You were right, Vi-- all that money.
我的埃迪會為我感到羞恥的。
My Eddie'd be ashamed of me.
我馬上回來，嗯？
I'll be right back, huh?
做夢沒什麼錯，艾達，嗯？
Nothing wrong with dreaming, Ada, hmm?
當我來到倫敦時，
When I came to London,
街道上鋪滿了我的夢想。
the streets were paved with my dreams.
[嘆氣]這就是你。
[sighs] That's what you are.
你是個夢想家。
You're a dreamer.
就像你臉上的鼻子一樣平淡。
Plain as the nose on your face.
[輕彈]
[lighter flicks]
[敲門聲]
[knocking]
放棄吧，維。我很好。
Give over, Vi. I'm all right.
男：哈里斯夫人？
MAN: Mrs. Harris?
愛德華·哈里斯夫人？
Mrs. Edward Harris?
是關於你丈夫的。
It's about your husband.
艾達：請坐。
ADA: Sit down, please.
哈里斯中士並未在行動中被宣布失?
Sergeant Harris wasn't declared missing in action
直到4月19日。
until April the 19th.
嗯，是的，那是我收到電報的時候。
Uh, yeah, that's when I got the telegram.
這是他生日的第二天。
It's a day after his birthday.
是的。
Ah, yes.
嗯，我們現在知道，
Well, um, as we now know,
1944 年 3 月 2 日，Polo Lima 326 航班墜毀，
Flight Polo Lima 326 crashed on March the 2nd, 1944,
意味著哈里斯中士得到了報酬
meaning that Sergeant Harris was paid
在他死後將近七個星期。
for almost seven weeks after his death.
在，嗯，每天六先令。
At, um, six shillings a day.
你是來告訴我的嗎？
Is that what you come to tell me?
畢竟這段時間。
After all this time.
我的埃迪欠你的錢？
That my Eddie owes you back pay?
當他一生中從未欠過一分錢時e.
When he never owed a penny in his life.
當他為國王和國家放棄生命時。
When he give up his life for king and country.
你有神經。
You got a nerve.
來到我家，喝我的茶，
Coming into my home, drinking my tea,
抹黑他的名字。
blackening his name.
-嗯... -你想要多少？
-Um... -How much do you want?
多少錢？然後你就可以離開了。
How much? And then you can leave.
我-我認為你搞錯了。
I-I think you've got the wrong end of the stick.
哦，我有嗎？好吧，我會告訴你
Oh, have I? Well, I'll tell you
你可以在一分鐘內把你的棍子推到哪裡，
where you can shove your stick in a minute,
- 如果你不小心。 -哦，天哪，不。嗯，我，呃……
-if you don't watch out. -Oh, golly, no. Um, I, uh...
我是來給你錢的 哈里斯夫人
I'm here to give you money, Mrs. Harris,
-不-不從你那裡拿走它。 -我受夠了...
-not-not to take it from you. -I've had enough of...
你說什麼？
What'd you say?
是的。對。
Y-Yes. Righto.
呃，你應該收到
Uh, you should have been receiving
a-自 1944 年以來的戰爭寡婦撫卹金。
a-a war widow's pension since 1944.
額，額，額，扣除這麼少。
It comes to quite a tidy sum, uh, with that small deduction.
只要你沒有再婚。
So long as you haven't remarried.
哦，放棄吧。
Oh, give over.
他可能隨時會回來，
He might have come back any minute,
我會看起來是正確的查理。
I'd have looked a right Charlie.
-[輕笑] -呃...
-[chuckles] -Uh...
出色地...
well...
[硬幣在桌子上叮噹作響]
[coins clink on table]
我想你最好坐下。
I suppose you'd better sit down.
畢竟喝了那杯茶。
Have that cup of tea after all.
嗯，沒有牛奶。
Um, no milk.
VI：她這輩子從來沒有做錯任何事，先生。
VI: She's never done a thing wrong her whole life, sir.
她因為一件衣服有點發瘋，
She went a bit crazy on account of some dress,
但她現在很好。
but she's fine now.
警察：沒什麼好擔心的。
POLICEMAN: Nothing to worry about.
-ADA：哦，你好。 -太太。哈里斯？
-ADA: Oh, hello. -Mrs. Harris?
你來告訴我我得到了皇冠上的珠寶？
You come to tell me I got the crown jewels?
她的頭腦仍然不正確。
She's still not right in the head.
幾乎。你遞過來的那個鑽石夾——
Almost. That diamond clip you handed in--
主人想給你獎勵
the owner wants to give you a reward
——作為一個誠實的公民。 -[笑]
-for being an honest citizen. -[laughs]
哦！先生，她是誠實的。
Oh! She is, sir, honest to a fault.
進來喝杯茶。
Come in and have a cup of tea.
不要介意我這樣做。謝謝你。
Don't mind if I do. Thank you.
哦，來吧，維。我們可以單膝跪地。
Oh, come on, Vi. We can have a knees-up.
阿奇：餵，等我一下。
ARCHIE: Oi, wait for me.
而且，呃，你可能想打破泡沫。
And, uh, you might want to break out the bubbly.
你還有幸運的一天嗎，阿奇？
You having another lucky day, Archie?
事實上，我是，你也是。
As a matter of fact, I am, and so are you.
消息傳得很快。
News travels fast.
所以，你賭那條兩條腿的狗……
So, that bet you put on that two-legged dog...
哦，是的，別……別擔心。
Oh, y-yeah, don't... don't worry about that.
我已經清醒過來了。
I've come to me senses.
[笑]：不，老闆在那裡，
[chuckles]: No, the boss was there,
所以我不得不拿錢，
so I had to take the money,
但我設法忍住了。
but I managed to hold back a tenner.
你不應該那樣做，阿奇。
You shouldn't have done that, Archie.
你可能遇到了麻煩。
You could have got into trouble.
所有的票噓聲，哈里斯夫人？
All tickety-boo, Mrs. Harris?
哦，對不起，我不知道你有公司。
Oh, sorry, I didn't realize you had company.
你好。這裡發生了什麼？
Hello. What's going on here?
-ADA：哦。 - 為了邁克的愛。
-ADA: Oh. -For the love of Mike.
——嗯，待會見。 -ADA：呃，不，阿奇，阿奇。
-Uh, I'll see you later. -ADA: Uh, no, Archie, Archie.
呃，你能給我一點時間嗎？
Uh, can you just give me a moment?
-它-這是個人的。 -[Vi 口哨]
-It-it's personal. -[Vi whistles]
- 水壺在召喚？ -啊，沒錯。
-That the kettle calling? -Ah, righto.
[門關閉]
[door closes]
這是怎麼回事？有事嗎？
What's going on? Something up?
說來話長。
It's a long story.
你在說什麼？
What were you saying?
所以，我拿了你的錢
So, I took your money
並在最後一場比賽中確定無疑。
and put it on a sure thing in the last race.
還有，嗯...
And, um...
......你的股份回來了，還有一點點。
...your stake back and a wee bit more.
哦，不，不，阿奇，我不能。
Oh, n-no, Archie, I couldn't.
-我... -這是你的錢。拿著。
-I... -It's your money. Take it.
養不下去了嗚嗚男人。
I can't keep it, woman.
那裡的 PC Plod 會有我的許可證。來吧。
PC Plod in there would have my license. Come on.
[笑]
[laughing]
只要答應我在軍團跳舞。
Just promise me a dance at the Legion.
謝謝，阿奇。
Thanks, Archie.
非常感謝。
Much obliged.
天哪。
Blimey.
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
[飛機嘎嘎作響]
[plane rattling]
我們在飛嗎？
Are we flying?
[對講鈴聲]
[intercom chimes]
乘務員：我們非常抱歉，
FLIGHT ATTENDANT: We're terribly sorry,
女士們先生們。
ladies and gentlemen.
似乎一台發動機有故障。
There seems to be a fault with one engine.
會有輕微延遲
There will be a slight delay
當我們嘗試解決問題時。
while we try and fix the problem.
延遲？
Delay?
多久？
How long?
我必須在一天之內到達那裡並回來。
I've got to be there and back in a day.
[輕輕打鼾]
[snores softly]
[喘氣，耳語]：哦，上帝。
[gasps, whispers]: Oh, God.
[喘氣]
[gasps]
巴黎。
Paris.
-[模糊的喋喋不休] -[按喇叭]
-[indistinct chatter] -[horn honks]
Righto，巴黎，我來了。
Righto, Paris, here I come.
這是一個相當古老的步行。
It's a fair old walk.
[交通隆隆聲]
[traffic rumbling]
-[男人咳嗽] -[Ada 吸鼻子]
-[man coughs] -[Ada sniffs]
【火車汽笛聲】
[train whistle blows]
[P.A. 的法語公告]
[announcement in French over P.A.]
哦。嗯...
Oh. Um...
你好。
bonjour.
請問你說什麼？
Beg your pardon?
[笑]
[laughs]
[男人笑]
[men laughing]
嘿。
Hey.
艾達：謝謝。是的。
ADA: Thank you. Yeah.
嗯，我是來買衣服的。
Um, I'm here to buy a dress.
來自迪奧。
From Dior.
-迪奧？ -[都在喃喃自語]
-Dior? -[all muttering]
啊，oui.Me也是。
Ah, oui.Me also.
[笑聲]
[laughter]
遠嗎——迪奧？
Is it far-- Dior?
哦……[嘆氣]
Oh... [sighs]
20分鐘。
20 minutes.
呃，但是在你喝酒之後，兩個小時。
Uh, but after you take wine, two hours.
[笑聲]
[laughter]
我帶你去那裡。
I walk you there.
[打嗝]
[burps]
明天早上，嗯？
Tomorrow morning, eh?
哦，不，不，謝謝。
Oh, no, no, thanks.
我不能，不。
I couldn't, no.
[咕嚕聲]
[grunts]
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
[男人笑]
[men laughing]
好吧，那就繼續吧。 [笑]
All right, go on, then. [laughs]
哦，天哪。 [笑]
Oh, blimey. [laughs]
[笑聲]
[laughter]
ADA：為什麼街上到處都是垃圾？
ADA: Why is all this rubbish on the streets?
米歇爾：大老闆出軌了……
MICHEL: The big boss cheats...
[說法語]
[speaks French]
- 工人，是嗎？ -是啊。
-The worker, yes? -Yeah, yeah.
工人說：“沒有了。”
The worker say, "No more."
賓門罷工了？
The binmen are on strike?
是的。
Ah, yes.
現在整個巴黎，呃，聞起來，呃……
Now all Paris, uh, smells, uh...
[聞]
[sniffs]
……呃，和我一樣。 [笑]
...uh, like me. [laughs]
[笑]
[laughing]
天啊。
Oh, God.
你是一個高貴的女人。
You are a noble woman.
請記住，在法國，工人為王。
And remember, in France, the worker is king.
[人群竊竊私語]
[crowd murmuring]
-[咕噥] -哦，小姐！
-[grunts] -Oh, miss!
你還好嗎，親愛的？
You all right, love?
-你弄傷你自己了？ -不。對不起。
-Did you hurt yourself? -No. Sorry.
謝謝你。
Thank you.
-你確定嗎？ -是的。
-Are you sure? -Yes.
哦。
Oh.
錯過？
Miss?
錯過！
Miss!
[人群竊竊私語]
[crowd murmuring]
-[門劉海關上] -ADA：不，小姐。
-[door bangs shut] -ADA: No, miss.
哦哦哦！錯過！
Ooh-ooh! Miss!
錯過？
Miss?
幹得好。
Here you go.
再一次，你救了我，夫人。
Once again, you save me, madame.
-[輕笑]：哦。 -對不起。我很晚了。
-[chuckles]: Oh. -I'm sorry. I'm very late.
-哦。 -謝謝。
-Oh. -Thank you.
沒關係。只要你是一體的。
It's all right. As long as you're in one piece.
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
哦。
Ooh.
哦，呃...
Ooh, uh...
哦。對不起，親愛的。
Oh. Excuse me, dear.
-我在哪裡可以找到連衣裙？ ——[輕聲喘氣]
-Where would I find the frocks? -[gasps softly]
女士，我擔心您的地址有誤。
I fear you have the wrong address, madame.
我會叫人給你指路。
I will call someone to show you the way.
-[鈴聲] -ADA：不，不，不。
-[ringing] -ADA: No. No, no.
對不起。我——我……我在找一件連衣裙。
Sorry. I'm-I'm... I'm after a frock.
其中一個是 500 磅的。
One of them 500-pound ones.
拜託，如果你能在這裡等一下，
Please, if you could wait over here,
有人會直接參加。
somebody will attend you directly.
[安靜的喋喋不休]
[quiet chatter]
現在，等一下。打擾一下。
Now, hang on. Excuse me.
夫人，我——我是第一個來的，在這批人之前。
Madame, I-I was here first, before any of this lot.
你沒聽說過排隊嗎？
Ain't you heard of queuing?
打擾一下。看，對不起。
Excuse me. Look, I'm sorry.
-請。 -我-我...我不是一個大驚小怪的人，
-Please. -I'm-I'm... I'm not one to make a fuss,
但我來自哪裡，
but where I come from,
女店員很樂意為您服務。
shopgirls are pleased to be of service.
-店員？ -[輕笑]
-Shopgirls? -[light laughter]
這位女士想買一件衣服。
This lady wishes to buy a dress.
引導她到合適的商店。
Direct her to a suitable shop.
去。
Go.
嗯，請讓我護送你出去。
Uh, please let me escort you out.
不，不，不，不，不，等一下。
No, no, no, no, no, hang on a minute.
我已經來了幾英里。
I've come miles.
節省了擦地板的每一分錢
Saved every penny scrubbing floors
我不知道是什麼所以我可以買這件連衣裙。
and I don't know what so I can buy this frock.
克里斯汀·迪奧 (Christian Dior) 禮服不是為了一分錢。
A Christian Dior gown is not for pennies.
正確的。
Right.
如果你覺得我沒錢...
If you think I ain't got the money...
那裡。
there.
哦我？？ l.
Oh l?? l.
-你是迪奧先生嗎？ -[輕笑]
-Are you Mr. Dior? -[chuckles]
哦，哦，不，我是法維爾先生，帳戶。
Oh, oh, no, I'm Mr. Fauvel, accounts.
讓我幫你解決...
Let me help you with the...
對不起，ch?艞re 夫人，但這是我的榮幸
Excuse me, ch?艞re madame, but it would be my honor
讓您以我的客人身份查看收藏。
to have you view the collection as my guest.
你在這。
There you are.
謝謝。
Merci.
我們可以？
Shall we?
哦。 [輕笑]
Oh. [chuckles]
[緊張地笑著]
[chuckles nervously]
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
它在這裡。
It's here.
謝謝你。
Thank you.
[鼓掌和噓聲]
[claps and shushes]
當你看到你想要的衣服時，
When you see the dress you want,
你可以在這裡寫下這個數字。
you can write the number down here.
哦。 [輕笑]
Oh. [chuckles]
[輕聲清嗓子]
[clears throat softly]
[嗅探]
[sniffing]
哦，我只是在欣賞你的扣眼。
Oh, I was just admiring your buttonhole.
哦。
Oh.
-是路易絲·奧迪爾。 -啊？
-It's Louise Odier. -Ah?
是的，它很可愛。適當的氣味。
Yes, it's lovely. Proper scent.
你是玫瑰鑑賞家嗎？
Are you a connoisseur of roses?
我丈夫埃迪在考文特花園工作，
My husband Eddie worked at Covent Garden,
花卉市場。
the flower market.
你知道，他總是把零碎的東西帶回家。
He was always bringing home odds and ends, you know.
[笑]玫瑰是我最喜歡的。
[chuckles] Roses are me favorite.
你想給你老婆穿件衣服嗎？
You after a dress for your wife?
哦。幸運的女人。
Ooh. Lucky woman.
我的妻子死了。
My wife is dead.
哦，對不起，先生。
Oh, I do beg your pardon, sir.
我笨拙的木屐。
My clumsy clogs.
我的埃迪和所有人。
My Eddie and all.
哦，嗯...
Oh, um...
但是，是的，呃，我和我的妻子會一起來這裡。
But yes, uh, my wife and I would come here together.
我喜歡看漂亮的衣服。
I like to see beautiful clothes.
當然還有美女。
And beautiful women, of course.
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
[艾達抽泣]
[Ada sniffling]
-[輕柔的管弦樂演奏] -[輕笑]：哦，我們開始吧。
-[soft orchestral music plays] -[chuckling]: Oh, here we go.
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
[掌聲]
[applause]
哦。
Ooh.
[人群竊竊私語]
[crowd murmuring]
哦，那太可愛了。
Oh, that's lovely.
[喘氣] 哦。
[gasps] Oh.
[掌聲]
[applause]
[顫抖]：哦，你會看。
[shuddering]: Oh, will you look.
[掌聲]
[applause]
哦，那太可愛了。
Oh, that's lovely.
[喘氣]
[gasps]
[嘆氣]
[sighs]
[瑪格麗特說法語]
[Marguerite speaking French]
瑪格麗特：V?共努斯。
MARGUERITE: V?韶nus.
- 那是什麼號碼？ -73。
-What number's that? -73.
-V? 是的。 -73。 V?共努斯。
-V?韶nus.Yes. -73. V?韶nus.
- 那是什麼號碼？ -89。
-What number's that? -89.
誘惑。
Temptation.
哦耶。
Oh, yeah.
[安靜，模糊的喋喋不休]
[quiet, indistinct chatter]
[激動的喋喋不休]
[excited chatter]
太棒了！
Bravo!
那傢伙是誰？
Who's that bloke?
嗯，這就是大師本人，迪奧先生。
Well, that's the master himself, Monsieur Dior.
繼續。
Go on.
-他看起來像我的送奶工。 -[笑]
-He looks like my milkman. -[laughs]
[安靜的喋喋不休]
[quiet chatter]
好吧，祝你好運，夫人。
Well, good luck, madame.
我希望你能找到你要找的東西。
I hope you find what you're looking for.
哦，好吧……[笑著說]
Oh, well... [chuckles]
這裡。
Here.
你不想保留它嗎？
You do not wish to keep it?
是的，它——它很可愛。謝謝你。
Yeah, it's-it's lovely. Thank you.
附魔?共。
Enchant?韶.
別管我。
Don't mind me.
- 是的，夫人？ -哦。
-Yes, madame? -Oh.
你做出選擇了嗎？
Have you made your selection?
是的。嗯……[笑著哭]
Yes. Um... [laughs]
89號，請。誘惑。
Number 89, please. Temptation.
當然。
Of course.
-請問你的名字是什麼。 -哈里斯。
-Your name, please. -Harris.
艾達·哈里斯夫人。
Mrs. Ada Harris.
我很抱歉，女士。
My apologies, madame.
-Excusez-moi。 -哦耶。
-Excusez-moi. -Oh, yeah.
-啊。 -哦。達達。
-Ah. -Oh. Ta-da.
哈里斯夫人，我很遺憾...
Madame Harris, I regret...
嗯，誘惑有一個困難。
Well, there is a difficulty with Temptation.
看來阿瓦隆夫人要求它。
It seems Madame Avallon demands it.
那怎麼做呢？你只有一件衣服？
How's that work, then? You only got the one dress?
對不起。夫人堅持排他性。
I'm sorry. Madame insists on exclusivity.
阿瓦隆夫人是我們最忠實的客戶之一。
Madame Avallon is one of our most devoted clients.
她的丈夫被稱為“垃圾之王”。
And her husband is known as "The King of Rubbish."
但如果你離開 Maison Dior 我們會很抱歉
But we would be so sorry if you were to leave Maison Dior
無需購買。
without a purchase.
你還在卡片上寫了數字73。
And you also wrote number 73 on your card.
-哦。 -V?共努斯。
-Oh. -V?韶nus.
是的，我從沒想過沒有比這更美麗的了。
Yeah, I never thought nothing could be more beautiful.
直到我看到誘惑。
Not till I saw Temptation.
一個很好的選擇，女士。
An excellent choice, madame.
是的。多少錢？
Yeah. How much is it?
V? 共 600,000 法郎。
V?韶nusis 600,000 francs.
安德烈？？？ 430 磅。
ANDRE??? 430 pounds.
包起來。我有一架飛機要趕。
Wrap it up. I got a plane to catch.
- 我遲到了一天。 ——【安德?共結結巴巴】
-I'm a day late as it is. -[Andr?韶 stammering]
哦，你不能有這件禮服。
Oh, you cannot have this gown.
哦，不要告訴我有人想要那種獨家的東西。
Oh, don't tell me someone wants that exclusive and all.
Mais Madame Harris，每一件衣服都是製作的
Mais Madame Harris, every dress is made
並為客戶單獨安裝。
and fitted individually for the client.
是的，這是高級時裝。
Yes, this is haute couture.
當然，我們會按照您所看到的那樣複製 V?共無，
We will, of course, reproduce V?韶nusexactly as you saw it,
但問題是……
but the thing is...
給我一個？
Make me one?
這需要多長時間？
How long's that gonna take?
好吧，至少兩週。
Well, at least two weeks.
哦。至少。
Ooh. At least.
需要幾個配件。
Several fittings are necessary.
什麼，離開我的人民兩週？
What, leave my people for a fortnight?
他們會找到其他人，然後我會流落街頭。
They'd find someone else, and then I'd be out on the streets.
[喘氣] Vite，Vite，去機場，然後。
[gasps] Vite, vite, to the airport, then.
如果你錯過了我不會原諒自己我們的航班。
I would not forgive myself if you missed your flight.
- 什麼，沒有我的裙子？ -Excusez-moi。
-What, without my dress? -Excusez-moi.
也許有朋友可以打電話？
Perhaps there is a friend you can call?
可以幫助您清潔的人。
Someone who can assist you with your cleaning.
嗯，嗯，有Vi，
Well, uh, there's Vi,
但我已經嘗試了她足夠的耐心。
but I've tried her patience enough as it is.
反正她不接電話。
Anyway, she's not on the phone.
呃，我們可以給她發個電報。
Uh, we might send her a telegram.
呃，哈里斯夫人，
Uh, Mrs. Harris,
呃，也許可以鼓勵
uh, it might be possible to encourage
裁縫和裁縫工作得快一點。
the cutter and seamstress to work a little faster.
或許，六夫人能給你一個星期的時間？
And Madame Vi could fill you in for one week, perhaps?
出色地...
Well...
你很善良，但我不能。
you're kind, but I can't.
反正我沒地方住。
Anyway, I got nowhere to stay.
我將不得不錯過它。
I'll have to give it a miss.
我姐姐走了。
My sister is away.
如果你...會接受，嗯，
If you... would accept, um,
你可以留在我的地方，呃，在我姐姐的房間裡。
you could stay at my place, uh, in my sister's room.
你是一個合格的天使，不是嗎？
You're a proper angel, aren't you?
這將是我的榮幸。
It'll be my pleasure.
嗯，我們可以立即測量您的尺寸。
Um, we can have your measurements taken at once.
N'est-ce pas，科爾伯特夫人？
N'est-ce pas, Madame Colbert?
來吧，哈里斯夫人。來。
Come, Madame Harris. Come.
-哦。 -我們必須快點。
-Oh. -We must be quick.
S'il vous pla? 銅噸。
S'il vous pla?銅t.
哦。 [輕笑]
Oh. [chuckles]
- 太棒了，夫人。 - 好極了。
-Bravo, madame. -Bravo.
[偷笑]
[chuckling]
-請，夫人。 -哦。
-Please, madame. -Oh.
你不明白這一切
You don't get all this hoo-ha
當你在 Woolworths 買一件羽絨服時。
when you buy a frock down Woolworths.
好吧，我可以告訴你這樣的事情
Well, I can tell you such things
也不是每天都在這裡發生。
do not happen every day here, either.
啊，必須有她的衣服的女士......
Ah, the lady who must have her dress...
[說法語]
[speaks French]
請你的外套。
Your coat, please.
哦。
Oh.
-Et le 開衫。 -是的，我卡迪。
-Et le cardigan. -Yeah, me cardy.
非常感謝。
Thank you very much.
哦。
Oh.
夫人有模特的比例。
Madame has the proportions of a model.
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
模型鐵路，更像。
Model railway, more like.
[笑聲]
[laughter]
彎曲位之一。
One of the curvy bits.
[笑聲繼續]
[laughter continues]
哦謝謝。
Oh, thank you.
非常感謝。
Thank you very much.
[嘆氣]
[sighs]
夫人？
Madame?
哦。 [輕笑]
Oh. [chuckles]
我可以送你一程嗎？
May I give you a lift?
哦，好吧，如果它不麻煩的話。
Oh, well, if it's no bother.
不。
No.
呃，我要去法維爾先生家。
Uh, I'm going to Mr. Fauvel's.
18 號，是的。這很容易。
The 18th, yes. That's easy.
- 哦，原諒這亂七八糟的。 -哦。 [輕笑]
-Oh, forgive the mess. -Oh. [chuckles]
他是你的朋友嗎，法維爾先生？
Is he a friend of yours, Mr. Fauvel?
不，不，我——我認識法維爾先生
No. No, I-I know Mr. Fauvel
只是作為簽署我支票的手。
only as the hand that signs my check.
哦。 [笑]
Oh. [laughs]
哦。
Oh.
[慢慢地]：L'tre et le n? 共蟻。
[slowly]: L'??tre et le n?韶ant.
這是，呃，“存在與不存在”。
It's, uh, "Being and Not Being."
我喜歡蜷縮在一個多汁的神秘之中。
I like to curl up with a juicy mystery meself.
[雙方都在笑]
[both chuckling]
哦，看，那裡是埃菲爾鐵塔。
Oh, look, there's the Eiffel Tower.
哦，那太可愛了。
Oh, that's lovely.
[模糊的喋喋不休]
[indistinct chatter]
哦。 [笑]
Oh. [laughs]
那是歌劇。
That's the opera.
我可以幫你拿行李嗎？
May I help you with your luggage?
[嘲笑] 還沒有。
[scoffs] Nothing in it yet.
哦。那是什麼，尼特？
Oh. That's something, innit?
哦。
Ooh.
我想他姐姐不知道拖把在哪裡。
I don't think his sister knows where the mop is.
某處必須有簸箕和刷子。
There must be a dustpan and brush somewhere.
娜塔莎：呃……
NATASHA: Uh...
哦。
Oh.
哦，你不必那樣做，親愛的。
Oh, you don't have to do that, love.
你一定有更好的事情要做。
You must have better things to do.
不，不是。
No, not really.
在 d?ofil?o 之後，總有
After the d?韶fil?韶,there's always
某種空虛感。
a certain feeling of emptiness.
哦。
Oh.
好吧，鴨子。 [輕笑]
All right, ducks. [chuckles]
哦。啊哈。
Oh. Aha.
-現在我們開始做生意了。 ——[都笑了]
-Now we're in business. -[both laugh]
安德烈？？？哦。
ANDRE??? Oh.
-太太。哈里斯？ -ADA：你好，親愛的。
-Mrs. Harris? -ADA: Hello, love.
安德烈？？？小姐。
ANDRE??? Mademoiselle.
ADA：她是個好工人。
ADA: She's a good worker.
我總能為你找到工作，我的女孩，
I can always find you a job, my girl,
如果建模不成功。
if the modeling don't work out.
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
不，不。
No, no.
哦！哦！ [呻吟]
Oh! Oh! [groans]
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
M-夫人哈里斯已經做好了晚餐。
M-Mrs. Harris has cooked the dinner.
你看起來可以吃一頓豐盛的大餐，
You look like you could do with a good square meal,
你們這一對。
the pair of you.
好吧，娜塔莎小姐還有其他事情要做。
Well, Mademoiselle Natasha has other engagements.
我敢肯定，Dior 的面孔總是出現在派對或首映式上。
I'm sure the face of Dior is always at a party or premiere.
還有晚會嗎？
There's a soir?韶elater.
來吧。格魯布起來了。
Come on. Grub's up.
我們到了。
Here we are.
不要讓它變冷。
Don't let it get cold.
-Bon 應用程序？ -Bon 應用程序？
-Bon app?韶tit. -Bon app?韶tit.
我愛迪的最愛。
My Eddie's favorite.
如果我們有一點肉汁就更好了。
Be even better if we had a bit of gravy.
嗯，這道菜叫什麼名字？
Um, and what's the dish named?
癩蛤蟆。
Toad-in-the-hole.
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
多多的書啊，法維爾先生。
What a lot of books, Mr. Fauvel.
安德烈？？？哦。
ANDRE??? Oh.
娜塔莎有一個軟木塞，一個謀殺之謎。
Natasha's got a corker, a murder-mystery.
不是嗎，鴨子？
Don't you, ducks?
我們應該說英語。
We should speak English.
哦耶。當然。
Oh, yeah. Of course.
嗯，我-我有興趣學習
Um, I-I'm interested to learn
娜塔莎小姐正在看書
that Mademoiselle Natasha is reading a book
——法國哲學家讓-保羅·薩特。 -哦。
-by the French philosopher Jean-Paul Sartre. -Oh.
作者要求我們考慮服務員的情況。
The author asks us to consider the case of the waiter.
服務員是服務員，還是只是一種表達
Is the waiter the waiter, or is it just an expression
服務員是什麼？
of what the waiter is?
嗯，同樣，我是會計嗎，
Um, similarly, am I the accountant,
還是外在的印象？
or is that an outward impression?
嗯，只有娜塔莎小姐最美嗎，
Um, is Mademoiselle Natasha only the most beautiful,
最精緻神聖的巴黎模特，或者...
the most exquisitely divine Parisian model, or...
還是門面後面還有另一個人？
Or is there another person behind the facade?
是的。
Yes.
哈里斯夫人是清潔工嗎？
Is Mrs. Harris the cleaner,
還是有更多可以定義她的存在？
or is there more to define her existence?
精確。
Exactement.
我是巴特西的清潔工。那裡沒有奧秘。
I'm a cleaner from Battersea. No mystery there.
呃，不，你是一個夢想的清潔工
Uh, no, you're a cleaner who dreams
世界上最美麗的禮服。
of the most beautiful gown in the world.
哦，夢想，嗯？
Oh, dreams, eh?
[笑]：天知道蔚要說什麼
[laughing]: God knows what Vi is gonna say
當她收到那封盛大的電報時。
when she gets that blooming telegram.
[都笑了]
[all laughing]
[敲門]
[knocking at door]
安德烈？？？哈里斯夫人？
ANDRE??? Mrs. Harris?
呃，請你幫我姐姐的衣服。
Uh, please help yourself to my sister's clothes.
哦，謝謝，愛。嗯，我沒事。
Oh, thanks, love. Um, I'm all right.
安德烈？？？嗯，她會堅持的。
ANDRE??? Uh, she would insist.
晚安。
Good night.
晚上愛。
Night, love.
甜蜜的夢。
Sweet dreams.
[深吸一口氣]
[inhales deeply]
-哦！ -[笑]
-Ooh! -[laughs]
站直，夫人。
Stand straight, madame.
-哦！ [笑] - 不，mais...
-Oh! [laughs] -Non, mais...
保持靜止。你為什麼要搬家？
Keep still. Why do you move?
對不起。對不起。
Sorry. Sorry.
[喘氣]瑪格麗特公主？
[gasps] Princess Margaret?
哦，我喜歡她。
Oh, I like her.
你可以從她的眼中看到一點惡作劇。
You can see a little bit of mischief in her eye.
我們尊貴的客戶需要我們最大的判斷力。
Our distinguished clients demand our utmost discretion.
這就是今天的全部內容。
That's all for today.
那一點點有很長的路要走，不是嗎？
Little bit of that one goes a long way, don't it?
什麼在吃她？
What's eating her?
嗯，客戶越大，難度越大。
Well, the more grand the client, the more difficult.
他們的願望必須始終得到滿足，
Their wishes must be accommodated always,
即使這意味著重新開始。
even if it means starting afresh.
- 他們直到交貨才付款。 -哦！
-And they do not pay until delivery. -Oh!
如果那時。
If then.
有很多薪水要找。
There are so many salaries to find.
面料，編織，刺繡，鈕扣
The fabric, braid, embroidery, buttons
一切都必須是最好的。
all must be the very best.
每個人都有壓力：
The pressure is on everyone:
關於法維爾先生和賬目，
on Mr. Fauvel and the accounts,
關於科爾伯特夫人和裁縫，
on Madame Colbert and the seamstresses,
即使是對迪奧先生本人，也總是有這樣的壓力。
even on Monsieur Dior himself, always such pressure.
嗯，難怪法維爾先生這麼高興
Well, no wonder Mr. Fauvel was so pleased
看看我的小手提包。
to see my little handbag.
好吧，事實上，哈里斯夫人，我們都害怕
Well, in truth, Madame Harris, all of us fear
迪奧之家不能再這樣下去了。
the House of Dior cannot keep going this way.
[講法語的人]
[man speaking French]
科爾伯特：哎呀，先生。
COLBERT: Oui, monsieur.
[科爾伯特說法語]
[Colbert speaking French]
你還好嗎，親愛的？
You all right, love?
醒醒醒醒。
Wakey, wakey.
他們在呼喚你。
They're calling for you.
哦。
Oh.
嗯，對不起。
Um, I'm sorry.
-我只是累了。 -嗯嗯。
-I'm just tired. -Mm-hmm.
你可以度過一個小假期。
You could do with a little holiday.
它已經在給我帶來善的力量。
It's doing me the power of good already.
嗯，那樣就太好了。
Yes, that would be nice.
獨自一人在海邊，
By myself at the seaside,
哪裡沒人...
where nobody...
對不起。
I'm sorry.
-我必須去。謝謝你。 -哦。
-I must go. Thank you. -Oh.
[用法語悄悄地繼續聊天]
[chatter continues quietly in French]
謝謝你。
Thank you.
[鳥鳴]
[birds chirping]
夫人，您的試衣怎麼樣？
How was your fitting, madame?
哦。
Oh.
好吧，如果不是我的老朋友，羅斯巴德先生。
Well, if it isn't my old pal, Mr. Rosebud.
我很遺憾我們沒有得到適當的介紹。
I regret we were not properly introduced.
侯爵侯爵·德·沙薩涅。
Marquis Hypolite de Chassagne.
哦。
Ooh.
巴特西的遺孀艾達哈里斯。
Ada Harris, widow of Battersea.
這個好人是誰？
Who's this fine fella?
-這是奈斯奎克。 -哦。
-This is Nesquik. -Oh.
所以，我相信迪奧先生會滿足你的心願嗎？
So, I trust Monsieur Dior fulfills your heart's desire?
哦，他們總是那麼善良。
Oh, they're being ever so kind.
路易絲·奧迪爾。我忘記了名字。
Louise Odier. I'd forgotten the name.
哦，我必須給你看點東西。
Oh, I must show you something.
拜託，我不會耽誤你太久的。
Please, I won't detain you long.
[艾達輕笑]
[Ada chuckles]
那麼，告訴我，你在巴黎過得怎麼樣？
So, tell me, how are you enjoying your time in Paris?
[鳥鳴]
[birds chirping]
[模糊的喋喋不休]
[indistinct chatter]
我的妻子喜歡 March? aux Fleurs。
My wife adored the March?韶 aux Fleurs.
艾達：嗯。
ADA: Mm.
我們幾乎到了最後才來到這裡。
We came here almost until the end.
現在已經七年了。
It's been seven years now.
我們修補，但我們不會忘記。
We mend, but we don't forget.
當你向世界展示你的 Dior 禮服時，
When you display your Dior dress to the world,
-這將是完美的。 -[輕笑]：哦。
-it will be perfection. -[chuckling]: Oh.
我的朋友 Vi 認為我很笨。
My pal Vi thinks I'm barmy.
[艾達輕笑]
[Ada chuckles]
“你要那件衣服幹什麼？
"What do you want that dress for?
你什麼時候穿？”[笑]
When are you gonna wear it?" [laughs]
哦，我不質疑你的願望
Oh, I do not question your desire
對於這樣質量的禮服，
for a gown of such quality,
即使只是為了你的眼睛。
even if it is for your eyes alone.
不，不，相反，我明白。
No, no, on the contrary, I understand.
你看，像這樣的玫瑰
You see, a rose like this one
或者像你這樣漂亮的禮服，
or a beautiful gown such as yours,
他們……他們回憶起那些日子
they... they recall the days
當我們正處於青春盛開的時候。
when we were in the full flower of our youth.
餵，別把我寫下來。
Oi, don't write me off just yet.
[都笑了]
[both laugh]
-哦，一千個道歉。 -[輕笑]：哦，不。
-Oh, a thousand apologies. -[chuckling]: Oh, no.
請允許我彌補。
Please, allow me to make amends.
今晚有安排嗎？
Have you any arrangements for tonight?
【活潑的民樂演奏】
[lively folk music playing]
呸呸呸？？？
Voil??.
哦謝謝。
Oh, thank you.
來點香檳？
Some champagne?
嗯，哦，是的，請。
Uh, oh, yes, please.
只是一滴。 [輕笑]
Just a drop. [chuckles]
謝謝你。
Thank you.
現在，你——你必須嚐嚐魚子醬。
Now, you-you must try the caviar.
哦。正確的。
Oh. Right.
-乾杯。 -乾杯。
-Cheers. -Cheers.
-很好，嗯？ -毫米。
-Nice, huh? -Mm.
嗯嗯，你好！ [笑]
Uh, oh, hello! [laughs]
[都笑了]
[both laughing]
我不認為這種裝束會愚弄任何人。你？
I don't think that getup's gonna fool anyone. Do you?
[來勢洶洶的音樂播放]
[menacing music playing]
可愛的女孩。
Lovely girls.
唔。很快，你就會看到多麼可愛。
Hmm. Soon, you'll see how lovely.
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
-[爵士樂演奏] -[歡呼，掌聲]
-[jazzy music playing] -[whooping, applause]
哦！哦。穩住。 [笑]
Ooh! Oh. Steady on. [laughs]
天哪，他們賺了他們的錢，他們是女孩。
Blimey, they earn their keep, them girls.
好吧，至少在我打掃衛生的時候，
Well, least when I'm cleaning,
我也不必微笑和脫衣。
I don't have to smile and strip as well.
[雙方都笑了]
[both chuckle]
Bonsoir，夫人。哈里斯。
Bonsoir,Mrs. Harris.
-娜塔莎。親愛的。 -[笑]
-Natasha. Hello, love. -[laughs]
你好。
Hello.
Bonsoir，小姐。
Bonsoir, mademoiselle.
-你想加入我們嗎？ -嗯，是的，請。
-Would you like to join us? -Uh, yes, please.
那你和誰在一起？
Who are you here with, then?
投資者。
Investors.
我逃跑了，但只是片刻。
I escape but only for a moment.
他們不會讓你整天和整夜都堅持下去。
They don't half keep you at it, all day and all night as well.
對於 Maison Dior，這是我的義務。
For Maison Dior, this is my obligation.
MARQUIS：啊，好吧，Dior 不僅僅是禮服。
MARQUIS: Ah, well, Dior is not just about gowns.
這也是關於優雅和頹廢
It's also about elegance and decadence
和巴黎的生活品味，還有……
and the savoir-vivreof Paris, and...
而你，娜塔莎小姐，你是寶石
and you, Mademoiselle Natasha, you are the jewel
- 這個迪奧皇冠。 -[艾達和娜塔莎輕笑]
-of this Dior crown. -[Ada and Natasha chuckle]
好吧，我寧願在家看書。
Well, I would prefer to be at home with a book.
ADA：你應該這麼說很有趣。
ADA: It's funny you should say that.
我把法維爾先生留在家裡看書。
I've left Mr. Fauvel at home reading a book.
它被稱為...
It was called...
“多管閒事”？類似的東西。
"Nosy"? Something like that.
-La naus? 共？ -不知道。
-La naus?韶e? -Don't know.
他為什麼容忍時裝屋
Why does he tolerate the fashion house
與他的薩特和智力世界相比？
compared to his world of Sartre and the intellect?
嗯，我-我認為他有他的理由。
Well, I-I think he has his reasons.
你喜歡這個節目嗎？
Do you enjoy the show?
是的，那個……最後的那個，她……
Yeah, the one... the one at the end, she...
她是我姑姑蒂爾達的死侍。
she's a dead ringer for my Aunt Tilda.
從後面。
From behind.
[笑聲]
[laughter]
嗯，這很可愛，但我應該去。
Well, this was lovely, but I should go.
謝謝你。
Thank you.
哦，就一分鐘，親愛的。
Oh, just-just a minute, love.
你的邊緣。
Your fringe.
有一點差距。
There's a little gap.
而已。
That's it.
你已經征服了。
You have made a conquest.
哦，離你遠點。
Oh, get away with you.
你敢於追隨你的夢想，哈里斯夫人。
You dare to follow your dreams, Mrs. Harris.
- 好極了。 -哦。
-Bravo. -Oh.
再見了，我的愛。
Bye, love.
-盆蘇爾。 - Bonsoir，娜塔莎。
-Bonsoir. -Bonsoir, Natasha.
-再來點香檳？ -哦，只是一滴。
-Some more champagne? -Oh, just a drop.
[笑]：我在 9 點 30 分讓我試衣。
[laughing]: I've got me fitting at 9:30.
[侯爵輕笑]
[Marquis chuckles]
-[音樂結束]-[歡呼和掌聲]
-[music ends] -[cheering and applause]
[歡快的打擊樂演奏]
[upbeat, percussive music playing]
[音樂消失]
[music fades]
[時鐘滴答作響]
[clock ticking]
[警笛聲響起]
[siren passing]
[遠處的男人大喊]
[man shouting in distance]
[喘氣，呻吟]
[gasps, groans]
[咕嚕聲]
[grunts]
[喘氣]哦，天哪！
[gasps] Oh, God!
-[按喇叭] -哦，戈登·貝內特！
-[horn honks] -Oh, Gordon Bennett!
哦，哦！
Oh, oh!
哦！哦！
Oh! Oh!
小心！
Careful!
-[輪胎尖叫] -哦，哦，哦！ [嗚咽]
-[tires screech] -Oh, oh, oh! [whimpers]
哦！
Oh!
[輪胎尖叫]
[tires squeal]
[工人喊]
[workers shouting]
[顫抖的嘆息]
[shuddering sigh]
我無法相信這一點。
I can't believe this.
[嗚咽]
[whimpering]
[whimpers]
對不起！
Sorry!
[喘氣]：對不起。對不起。
[panting]: Sorry. Sorry.
-我很抱歉。 -不不不。
-I'm so sorry. -No, no, no.
這是不可能的，根本不可能。
This is not possible, not at all.
不，不，不，求你了，我-我……我從不遲到。我...
No, no, no, please, I-I'm... I'm never late. I...
R-真的，我不是。我從不遲到。對不起。
R-Really, I'm not. I'm never late. Sorry.
你要求我們，“Vite，vite，vite，”
You demand of us, "Vite, vite, vite,"
但你沒有尊重。
but you have no respect.
不，這是做不到的。
No, this cannot be done.
一點也不。
Not at all.
現在我離開了。
Now I depart.
這就結束了。
This is finished.
不不不不。請，請，請，請，卡爾先生？
No, no, no, no. Please, please, p-please, Mr. Carr?韶.
科爾伯特夫人，請。
Madame Colbert, please.
卡爾?少先生拒絕繼續。
Monsieur Carr?韶 refuses to proceed.
我能做些什麼？
What can I do?
ADA：不，不，當然，我...
ADA: No. No, of course, I...
不，我明白。
No, I understand.
[結結巴巴]：是的，我當然知道。我願意。
[stammering]: Yeah, of course I do. I do.
[抽鼻子]
[sniffles]
迪奧，它不僅僅是一件禮服。
Dior, it's-it's not just a gown.
這是，嗯...
It's, um...
這是所有的優雅和 - 和精明等等。
It's all the elegance and-and the savvy and all that.
我——我知道。
I-I know that.
我會看看可以做些什麼來退還您的押金。
I will see what can be done to return your deposit.
不，我不...
No, I don't...
我-我...
I-I...
我不想...我不想讓我存款。
I don't want... I don't want me deposit.
正確的香檳查理，不是嗎？
Right Champagne Charlie, aren't I?
為我服務，過著高尚的生活。
Serves me right, living the high life.
我尊重你們，你們所有人。
I do respect you, all of you.
沒關係，嗯？
Never mind, eh?
謝謝，親愛。
Thanks, love.
你一直都那麼善良。
You've been ever so kind.
哈里斯夫人，你願意去看看工作室嗎
Madame Harris, would you care to see the atelier
在你離開之前？
before you leave?
哦。 [輕笑]
Ooh. [chuckles]
-您好，女士們。 -女人：你好。
-Bonjour, mesdames. -WOMAN: Bonjour.
所以，這個房間是用來切割的。
So, this room is for cutting.
-女人：你好。 -早晨。
-WOMAN: Bonjour. -Morning.
高級定制結構。
Structure du couture.
瑪格麗特：非結構化時裝。
MARGUERITE: Unstructured couture.
[機器安靜地嘎嘎作響]
[machines rattling quietly]
瑪格麗特：Passementerie。
MARGUERITE: Passementerie.
瑪格麗特：普拉馬西耶。
MARGUERITE: Plumassier.
瑪格麗特：布羅德麗。
MARGUERITE: Broderie.
[瑪格麗特說法語，聲音迴響]
[Marguerite speaking French, voice echoing]
這不是縫紉。
It's not sewing.
它正在製造月光。
It's making moonlight.
[輕笑]
[chuckles softly]
我去天堂了嗎？
Have I gone to heaven?
[笑]
[laughs]
[笑聲]
[laughter]
[笑聲停止]
[laughter stops]
[安靜的喋喋不休]
[quiet chatter]
[工人在外面大喊]
[workers shouting outside]
我站在迪奧先生的肩膀上
I have stood at Monsieur Dior's shoulder
十年不眠不休，
day and night for ten years,
自從 le ma? Copper 推出了他的第一個系列。
since le ma?銅treunveiled his first collection.
世界上最時尚的女性
The most fashionable women in the world
來到蒙田大道。
come to the Avenue Montaigne.
皇室和妓女，
Royalty and courtesans,
瘦的, 胖的, 年輕的, 老的, 醜陋的,
thin, fat, young, old, ugly,
或帶有某種je ne sais quoi。[笑聲]
or with a certain je ne sais quoi.[chuckles]
唔。
Hmm.
但是還有你，哈里斯夫人。
But then there is you, Mrs. Harris.
我作為女導演的所有時間，
All my time as directress,
我從來沒有遇到過像你這樣的人。
I have never encountered anyone like you.
[笑]：哦。
[chuckles]: Oh.
在我的生活中，你會遇到各種各樣的。
In my walk of life, you meet all sorts.
作為一個好老闆，我必須讓我的員工開心，
As a good boss, I must keep my workers happy,
他們的願望是完成你的衣服。
and their wish is to complete your dress.
[笑]：哦。非常感謝。
[chuckles]: Oh. Much obliged.
所以你會禮貌地回答我的問題，不是嗎？
So you will do me the courtesy of answering my questions, no?
是的。
Yeah.
哦。喝光。
Oh. Bottoms up.
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
你為什麼來這裡，哈里斯夫人？
Why do you come here, Mrs. Harris?
E隊idemment，有錢有名的人一定要被看到，被欽佩，被複製。
E??隊idemment,the rich and titled must be seen, admired, copied.
但是這件你如此渴望的Dior連衣裙，
But this Dior dress that you desire so much,
你會在哪裡穿？
where will you wear it?
在維也納歌劇院舞會還是夏洛特皇后舞會？
At the Vienna Opera Ball or Queen Charlotte's?
你會穿它擦地板嗎？
Will you wear it to polish floors,
還是你會把它關在你的小衣櫃裡？
or will you keep it shut in your little wardrobe?
Dior 連衣裙的設計目的是令人驚喜和愉悅。
A Dior dress is designed to astonish and delight.
哈里斯夫人，你會怎麼做？
How will you do that, Mrs. Harris?
你……[笑著哭]
You... [chuckles]
原諒我這麼說，但你是無名之輩，隱形的。
Forgive me for saying this, but you are nobody, invisible.
你將如何賦予這件衣服應有的生命？
How will you give this dress the life it deserves?
那是我的夢想。
It's my dream.
我的錢和其他人一樣好。
And my money's as good as anybody else's.
Bien s?抭r.唔。
Bien s?抭r. Hmm.
你可以買你的夢想，但你會用它做什麼？
You may buy your dream, but what will you do with it?
[敲門]
[knocking at door]
-Oui，entrez。 -[門打開]
-Oui, entrez. -[door opens]
哈里斯夫人，這些是給你的。
Mrs. Harris, these are for you.
哦。
Ooh.
來自侯爵先生。
From Monsieur le Marquis.
[笑]：哦。
[chuckles]: Oh.
他希望你明天來喝茶。
He wishes that you visit for tea tomorrow.
沙薩涅侯爵？
Le Marquis de Chassagne?
但是……[輕笑]他沒有接待任何人。
But... [chuckles] he receives nobody.
但我什麼都不是，不是嗎？
But I am nobody, aren't I?
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
我從沒想過像迪奧這樣的地方會有問題。
I never thought a place like Dior would have problems.
我看到了那件衣服，
I saw that dress,
我想到了夢想和童話。
and I thought of dreams and fairy tales.
[笑]是的，我們就像一個童話故事。
[chuckles] Yes, we are like a fairy tale.
可愛但不真實。
Lovely but not real.
今天有那個地方嗎？
Is there a place for that today?
哦，我們需要我們的夢想。
Oh, we need our dreams.
現在比以往任何時候都更。
Now more than ever.
如果你能擁有這個，你為什麼需要Dior？
If you can have this, why do you need Dior?
高級定制時裝對我們和我們的客戶來說是一種虛榮心。
Haute couture is a vanity for us and our clients.
事實上，我認為迪奧之家無法生存。
In truth, I don't think the House of Dior can survive.
不，親愛的，那將是一場悲劇。
No, love, that would be a tragedy.
你不能允許這種情況發生。
You can't allow that to happen.
嗯，我有個主意，
Well, I have an idea,
但它需要一種新的思維方式。
but it requires a new way of thinking.
什麼？ Bossy Boots 擋路了？
What? Bossy Boots in the way?
科爾伯特夫人，她守衛著聖殿。
Madame Colbert, she guards the temple.
她讓清潔工買了一件迪奧禮服。
She let a cleaning lady buy a Dior gown.
有錢能使鬼推磨。
Money talks.
是的，你知道它說什麼，
Yes, and you know what it says,
所以你必須做點什麼。
so you have to do something about it.
我知道你可以。你永遠那麼聰明。
I know you can. You're ever so clever.
你是唯一一個相信的人。
You're the only one who believes.
[點擊舌頭，輕笑]
[clicks tongue, chuckles]
-[歡呼和掌聲] -這裡發生了什麼事？
-[cheering and applause] -What's going on here?
它看起來就像首映式一樣。
It looks like a premiere.
艾達：哦！
ADA: Ooh!
哦，令人興奮。 [輕笑]
Oh, exciting. [chuckles]
哦，那是讓·法布爾，電影明星。
Oh, that's Jean Fabre, the movie star.
[歡呼]
[cheering]
嗯，他不知道嗎？
Mm, and don't he know it?
[雙方都笑了]
[both chuckle]
[歡呼，吹口哨]
[cheering, whistling]
哦，是娜塔莎！哦！
Oh, it's Natasha! Oh!
-娜塔莎！哦哦哦！ -你在幹什麼？不，不。
-Natasha! Ooh-ooh! -What are you doing? No, no.
-ADA：娜塔莎！ -安德烈？？？不。
-ADA: Natasha! -ANDRE??? No.
你好。
Hello.
晚上好，哈里斯夫人。
Good evening, Mrs. Harris.
你看起來很可愛。
You look lovely.
謝謝你。
Thank you.
Bonsoir，法維爾先生。
Bonsoir, Monsieur Fauvel.
Bonsoir. 嗯，我們不知道你是，呃......
Bonsoir.Um, we didn't know you were, uh...
我們只是路過。
We were just passing.
那麼，你們兩個今晚在做什麼？
So, what are you two doing this evening?
-ADA：哦，好吧……哦。 -娜塔莎。
-ADA: Oh, well... Oh. -Natasha.
娜塔莎：對不起。我——我必須走了。
NATASHA: I'm sorry. I-I must go.
很高興見到你。
It was great to see you.
哦耶。塔塔，愛。
Oh, yeah. Ta-ta, love.
[歡呼]
[cheering]
[相機點擊]
[camera clicks]
我認為這只是為了展示。
I think it's just for show.
我不確定他是不是適合結婚的那種。
I'm not sure that he's the marrying kind.
哈里斯夫人，我-我求求你了，
Mrs. Harris, I-I beg of you,
你-你需要停止這種耦合的事情
you-you need to stop this coupling thing
——在我屈辱而死之前。 -哦...
-before I die of humiliation. -Oh...
請。足夠的！
Please. Enough!
好的。我不是聾子。
All right. I'm not deaf.
我當然愛上了娜塔莎。
Of course I'm in love with Natasha.
我的意思是，誰不是？
I mean, who isn't?
對不起，生活不全是月光和電影。
I'm sorry, but life is not all moonlight and movies.
為什麼不能呢？
Why can't it be?
我獨自度過了太久，希望我的生活消失。
I've spent too long on my own, wishing my life away.
你不想做同樣的事情。
You don't want to do the same thing.
哈里斯夫人，我認為你的浪漫夢想
Mrs. Harris, I think your dreams of romance
非常適合巴黎。
fit Paris very well.
原諒我，但也許是你
Forgive me, but perhaps it is you
?愿意談戀愛。
who wishes to be in love.
你必須照顧自己的心。
You who must attend to your own heart.
ADA：來吧，Eddie，說點什麼，親愛的。
ADA: Come on, Eddie, say something, love.
試著理解這一點，因為我做不到。
Try and make some sense of this, 'cause I can't.
[嘆氣]
[sighs]
這都是你做的。
This is all your doing.
準備好讓你的女孩去巴黎。
Coming up with the readies to get your girl to Paris.
[短笑]
[short chuckle]
巴黎。
Paris.
去見某人？
To meet someone?
[哼著小調]
[hums a tune]
啊。
Ah.
我們可以？
Shall we?
Dior 的女孩說我的裙子快完成了。
The girls at Dior say my dress is almost finished.
是的。明天吧。
Yeah. Maybe tomorrow.
然後我會... 我會回家。
And then I'll be... I'll be back off home.
是的，它很可愛。
Yeah, it's lovely.
[笑]：真的，真的很可愛。
[chuckling]: Really, really lovely.
那個垃圾女人歡迎她。
That rubbish lady's welcome to hers.
[都笑了]
[both laugh]
諷刺的是。
And here's the irony.
迪奧先生為美女譜寫精美詩篇
Monsieur Dior makes exquisite poems for beautiful women
慶祝他們的新鮮和完美
in celebration of their freshness and perfection
只是看到他們被老頑童帶走。
only to see them carried away by old frumps.
就像那個可怕的阿瓦隆夫人一樣。
Like that dreadful Madame Avallon.
哦耶。
Oh, yeah.
然而，當然，有些人保留
Whereas, of course, there are those who retain
某個je ne sais quoi，
a certain je ne sais quoi,
一種難以言喻的魅力。
an indefinable allure.
-[門打開] -啊。
-[door opens] -Ah.
請允許我向您介紹一壺英國茶。
Allow me to present to you a pot of English tea.
哦，只是工作。
Oh, just the job.
唔。謝謝，瑪麗亞。
Hmm. Merci, Maria.
現在我們讓鍋沖泡。
And now we let the pot brew.
- 那是正確的形式，是嗎？ - 那是票。
-Is that the correct form, yes? -That's the ticket.
我得給你織個茶壺。
I'll have to knit you a tea cozy.
[雙方都笑了]
[both chuckle]
是的，出於我一直不清楚的原因，
Yes, for reasons that were never clear to me,
我六歲時被派去
I was sent as a boy of six
去溫莎的寄宿學校，
to a boarding school in Windsor,
這就是我喜歡茶的地方
and that's where I acquired a taste for tea
以及所有的英語。
and of all things English.
在我們等待的時候，
While we wait,
有件事我想讓你看看。
there's something I would like you to see.
跟我來。
Come with me.
那裡。
There.
ADA [輕笑]：哦。哦。
ADA [chuckling]: Oh. Oh.
六歲，你這個可憐的小傢伙。
Six years old, you poor mite.
嗯，家也好不了多少。
Well, home was not much better.
但是，是的，我受苦了。
But yes, I suffered.
我是一個軟弱的小男孩，永遠被欺負。
I was a weak little boy, perpetually bullied.
哦。 [輕笑]
Oh. [chuckles softly]
你知道，我一看到你，
You know, as soon as I saw you,
我在心裡感受到了這種聯繫。
I felt this connection in my heart.
我不知道，也許...
I don't know, perhaps...
你的笑容，你的善良，你的...
your smile, your kindness, your...
你的英語幽默。
your English humor.
我知道你讓我想起了一個人，
I knew you reminded me of someone,
一個對我來說非常親愛的人，但誰？
someone very dear to me, but who?
就在昨天，當我搜索我的記憶時，
And only yesterday, as I searched my memories,
我是否意識到有一個人照顧我。
did I realize there was a person who took care of me.
她的生活是一種不知疲倦的苦差事，
Her life was one of tireless drudgery,
然而她卻抽空安慰我，擦乾我的眼淚。
and yet she found the time to comfort me and dry my tears.
她的名字是馬多克斯夫人，
Her name was Mrs. Maddox,
但我們習慣稱她為拖把夫人。
but we used to call her Mrs. Mops.
那裡。 [輕笑]
There. [chuckles]
我、我讓你想起了拖把夫人？
I-I remind you of Mrs. Mops?
-是的。 - 清潔工？
-Ah, yes. -The cleaner?
拖把太太擦乾了我的眼淚，讓我又笑了，
Mrs. Mops dried my tears and made me smile again,
哈里斯夫人，這幾天你也一樣。
as you have, Mrs. Harris, these past few days.
我真希望我的德爾芬能認識你。
I do wish my Delphine could have known you.
你看，你給有需要的人安慰
You see, you give comfort to those in need
不求任何回報。
without asking anything in return.
那正確嗎？
Is that right?
-你就是這樣看我的嗎？ -[輕笑]
-Is that how you see me? -[chuckles]
你明白為什麼我們之間有聯繫嗎？
You see why there is a connection between us?
現在，讓我們喝杯英式茶，好嗎？
Now, let's have a nice cup of English tea, shall we?
呃，不，謝謝。
Uh, no, thank you.
我最好相處融洽。
I'd best be getting along.
他們在沙龍等我。
They're expecting me at the salon.
[結結巴巴]
[stammers]
瑪格麗特？
Marguerite?
怎麼了？
What's the matter?
[工人們繼續喊]
[workers continue shouting]
在你去。
In you go.
你讓所有這些女孩離開是為了什麼？
What's this about you letting all these girls go?
哦。你還好嗎，親愛的？
Ooh. You all right, love?
科爾伯特：沒有必要
COLBERT: It would not be necessary
如果他們像你一樣免費工作。
if they worked for free, as you do.
他們需要他們的工作。他們有家庭要養活。
They need their jobs. They've got families to feed.
原諒我。
Excusez-moi.
是的，這很可悲，但這不關你的事。
Yes, it is very sad, but this is not of your concern.
好吧，我們會看到的。
Well, we'll see about that.
拜託，夫人，您已經到達
Please, madame, you have reached
走進這個機構的每一個角落。
into every corner of this establishment.
現在，我堅持要你尊重我們的隱私。
Now, I insist that you respect our privacy.
唔。
Hmm.
你要去哪裡，哈里斯夫人？
Where are you going, Mrs. Harris?
去見老闆。
To see the boss.
-你不能。不-來吧，女孩們。
-You cannot. No. -Come on, girls.
-科爾伯特：拜託。不。-跟我來。維特，維特。
-COLBERT: Please. No. -Follow me. Vite, vite.
[機器嘎嘎作響]
[machines rattling]
來了，姑娘們。來吧。
Here we go, girls. Come on.
下工具。
Down tools.
來，到我身後。加入我們。
Come on, get behind me. Join us.
是的，今天得到了一份非常重要的工作。
Yeah, got a really important job today.
-哦，你看起來很可愛，但是來吧。 -太太。哈里斯！
-Ooh, you look lovely, but come on. -Mrs. Harris!
- 來做這件事我。 -太太。哈里斯！
-Come and do this for me. -Mrs. Harris!
你必須立即停止。
You must stop this at once.
你不知道你在做什麼。
You have no idea what you are doing.
哦，是的，我願意。
Oh, yes, I do.
這叫罷工。
It's called a strike.
[笑]
[laughs]
對了，女士們，加油。
Right, ladies, come on.
跟著我。沒時間了，親愛的。
Follow me. No time for that, dear.
餵！無需推搡。來吧。
Oi! No need to push and shove. Come on.
[安德烈? 說法語]
[Andr?韶 speaking French]
安德烈，你站起來吧？有工作要做。
On your feet, Andr?韶. There's work to be done.
哈里斯夫人，我求求你，不要這樣做。
Mrs. Harris, I beg of you, do not do this.
這是你的機會，安德烈？少，還有多少機會
This is your chance, Andr?韶, and how many chances
-你有生之年嗎？ -不，看...
-do you get in your lifetime? -No, look...
迪奧先生，請佔用您十分鐘的時間。
Monsieur Dior, ten minutes of your time, please.
這就是 Fauvel 先生拯救公司所需要的一切。
That's all Mr. Fauvel needs to save the company.
我？我-我是什麼...
Me? What do I-I...
加油，寵物。你能行的。告訴他你的計劃。
Go on, pet. You can do it. Tell him your plan.
-呃... -繼續。
-Uh... -Go on.
[嘆氣，結巴]
[sighs, stammers]
與其讓世界來到蒙田大道，
Rather than the world coming to Avenue Montaigne,
迪奧必須走向世界
Dior must go out to the world
為所有人提供一系列商品。
with a range of goods available to all.
呃，香水，絲襪，奢侈品……
Uh, perfume, stockings, luxury that...
普通女人買得起的。
that the ordinary woman can afford.
哎。
Oui.
什麼？
What?
啊對。
Oh, right.
祝你好運，親愛的。
Good luck, love.
[鎖定點擊]
[lock clicks]
-[工人喊] -Merci。
-[workers shouting] -Merci.
[清嗓子]
[clears throat]
[嘆氣]
[sighs]
但是今天，有一個新的女人，
But today, there's a new woman,
一個知道自己想要什麼的現代女性
a modern woman who knows what she wants
並且需要能夠購買。
and needs to be able to buy it.
今天，有哈里斯夫人。
Today, there's Mrs. Harris.
[笑]：哦。
[chuckles]: Oh.
ma? 銅樹同意我們的計劃意味著，
The ma?銅tre'sagreement to our plan means that,
我們不僅不會失去工作，還需要更多。
far from losing jobs, we will need more.
很多很多很多。
Many, many more.
[歡呼]
[cheering]
女人：太棒了！
WOMAN: Bravo!
你確定這是正確的街道嗎？
Are you sure this is the right street?
一定是。這是我每個月寄給她支票的地方。
Must be. This is where I send her check every month.
裡面不會有一點灰塵。
There won't be a speck of dust inside.
- 你可以賭上你的生命。 -[附近有狗叫]
-You can bet your life. -[dog barking nearby]
-安德烈？？？就是這個。 -[汽車通行證]
-ANDRE??? This is it. -[car passes]
不。
No.
讓我安心。
Leave me in peace.
一句話。
Just a word.
為什麼？我承認。
Why? I concede.
勝利屬於你，哈里斯夫人。
The victory is yours, Mrs. Harris.
我的丈夫——他在戰爭中受傷了。
My husband-- he was damaged in the war.
他需要不斷的照顧。
He requires constant care.
你要么做要么付錢。
Which you either do or pay for.
難怪你得到了所有的正面。
No wonder you got all that front on you.
請說出你想說的話。
Say what you want, please.
女士，我很抱歉冒犯了您。
Madame, I'm so sorry to have offended you.
我對你懷有最崇高的敬意，它是
I hold you in the highest regard, and it was
我從來沒有打算強迫改變......
never my intention to force a change on...
你描述的未來非常有意義，
The future you describe makes perfect sense,
但我不想參與其中。
but I want no part of it.
安德烈？？？呃，不，請。
ANDRE??? Uh, no, please.
你一定不要想離開。
You must not think of leaving.
也許我的帖子太久了，
Perhaps I have been too long in my post,
太長的隱形女人身後的偉人。
too long the invisible woman behind the great man.
[笑] 戰鬥的談話。
[chuckles] Fighting talk.
你走吧，姑娘。
You go, girl.
我不是像你這樣的革命者，哈里斯夫人。
I'm not a revolutionary like you, Mrs. Harris.
我只是希望一個人呆著。
I simply wish to be left alone.
嗯，那是......這一切都很好，花花公子，
Well, that's... that's all fine and dandy,
上帝知道你應得的，
and Lord knows you deserve it,
但你知道沒有你它會分崩離析，不是嗎？
but you know it'll fall apart without you, don't you?
相信我，我已經看過一遍又一遍。
Trust me, I've seen it over and over.
當女士起身離開時，紳士不會持續十分鐘。
When the lady ups and leaves, the gent don't last ten minutes.
你是需要的。
You're needed.
現在比以往任何時候都更。
Now more than ever.
還有誰會保持現狀？
Who else is gonna keep things up to scratch?
[偷笑]：不是安德烈？少或迪奧先生。
[laughing]: Not Andr?韶 or Monsieur Dior.
兩個男人會知道什麼？
What would two men know about that?
你和我，你知道，我們是豆莢裡的兩顆豌豆。
You and me, you know, we're two peas in a pod.
我們清理每個人的爛攤子
We clean up everybody's mess
讓花園裡的一切都變得可愛。
and make everything in the garden lovely.
我們是他們所依賴的人。
We're the ones they rely on.
他們甚至不知道我們在做什麼，
They don't even know what we do,
但就像雞蛋一樣肯定是雞蛋，沒有我們，
but as sure as eggs is eggs, without us,
這一切都發生了。
it all goes tits up.
[輕笑]
[chuckles softly]
或許可以和 le ma 交談一下？
Perhaps a conversation with le ma?銅treis required.
也許。 [輕笑]
Perhaps. [chuckles softly]
明天，你告訴娜塔莎你的感受。
And tomorrow, you tell Natasha how you feel.
哦，但是娜塔莎小姐已經離開了迪奧。
Oh, but Mademoiselle Natasha has left Dior.
她要離開巴黎了。
She's leaving Paris.
像你一樣，哈里斯夫人，她希望追隨她的夢想。
Like you, Mrs. Harris, she wishes to follow her dream.
繼續尋找，親愛的。她一定在某個地方。
Keep looking, love. She's got to be here somewhere.
她走了。這是最好的。
She's gone. It's for the best.
你會得到自己
You're gonna get yourself
如果您不這樣做，請在一分鐘內將一個好的夾子繞在耳朵上...
a good clip round the ear in a minute if you don't...
不掛斷。
Hang on.
等一下。我知道。
Hang on a minute. I know.
【火車汽笛聲】
[train whistle blares]
這裡。
Here.
哦。
Oh.
[笑]：哦。迪奧夫人。
[chuckles]: Oh. Madame Dior.
壯麗的。
Magnifique.
哦，好吧，你自己還不錯。
Oh, well, not so bad yourself.
[笑聲]
[laughter]
嗯，我們在找一個女孩。
Uh, we're looking for a girl.
嗯，她……她有點不高興。
Um, she's... she's a bit upset.
嗯...
Um...
她是迪奧的模特。
She's a Dior model.
-哦，娜塔莎。 -娜塔莎。
-Oh, Natasha. -Natasha.
這輩子，不適合我。
This life, it's-it's not for me.
ADA：不，當然不是。
ADA: No, of course it isn't.
固定在基座上，
Stuck on a pedestal,
像一個漂亮的洋娃娃一樣四處遊蕩。
paraded around like a beautiful doll.
任何人都可以看到女孩不想要它。
Anyone can see the girl doesn't want it.
哈里斯夫人是對的。
Mrs. Harris is right.
這不是我。
It's not who I am.
正如薩特所說，你——你發現自己很矛盾
As Sartre would say, y-you find yourself conflicted
在 tre-en-soi 和 tre-pour-soi 之間。
between ??tre-en-soi et ??tre-pour-soi.
在“自為”和“自為”之間。
Between "for itself" and "in itself."
Etre-en-soibeing 人類生活的那些方面
E??tre-en-soibeing those aspects of human life
涉及意識，
that involves consciousness,
而物理事實是 tre-pour-soi。
whereas physical facts are ??tre-pour-soi.
娜塔莎：在這種情況下，
NATASHA: In which case,
事情將是他們不是的。
things would be what they are not.
精確。
Exactement.
事物本來就不是，
Things are what they are not,
他們不是他們不是的。
and they're not what they're not.
安德烈，看在上帝的份上，親吻她吧。
Andr?韶, for God's sake, just kiss her.
是的。看在上帝的份上，親我一下。
Yes. For God's sake, just kiss me.
[男人笑]
[men chuckling]
唔。
Hmm.
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
[嘆氣]
[sighs]
迪奧夫人，你在巴黎沒有找到愛情嗎？
You did not find love in Paris, Madame Dior?
-不好了。不。-哦。 [輕笑]
-Oh, no. No. -Oh. [chuckles]
我以為為時已晚，但...
I thought it was too late, but...
...現在我不太確定。
...now I'm not so sure.
[雙方都在笑]
[both chuckling]
-[自行車鈴聲] -[安靜的喋喋不休]
-[bicycle bell dings] -[quiet chatter]
[火車嘎嘎作響]
[train rattling]
-親愛的。 -女人：你好，艾達。
-Hello, love. -WOMAN: Hello, Ada.
[門吱吱作響]
[door creaks]
[嘆氣]
[sighs]
[流水]
[water running]
[敲門]
[knocking at door]
-[敲門聲] -哦。好吧，好吧。
-[loud pounding at door] -Oh. All right, all right.
戈登·貝內特。
Gordon Bennett.
-[敲門聲繼續] -好吧。
-[knocking continues] -All right.
[笑]：好吧。
[laughing]: All right.
哦，你好，愛。進來。
Oh, hello, love. Come in.
哦，感謝上帝，你回來了。
Oh, thank God you're back.
哦，好吧，不長。
Oh, well, not long.
你要一杯茶嗎？
Do you want a cuppa?
沒時間。
No time.
-這是緊急情況。 -哦。正確的。
-This is an emergency. -Oh. Right.
好吧，好吧，深呼吸，告訴我發生了什麼事。
Okay, well, deep breath and tell me what's up.
我不能去，但如果我不...
I can't go, but if I don't...
哦，留下好印像很重要，你知道嗎？
Oh, it's so important to make a good impression, you know?
我願意。你想給誰留下深刻印象？
I do. Who you trying to impress?
製片人康戈爾德先生。
Mr. Korngold, the producer.
我要和他搭檔去皇家咖啡館參加盛大的晚宴。
I'm to partner him to the big dinner at the Caf?韶 Royal.
-哦。 -每個人都會在那裡。
-Ooh. -Everybody will be there.
這是一個無價的機會。
It's a priceless opportunity.
但看。
But look.
哦，嗯，是的，它有點……有點皺巴巴的，
Oh, well, yeah, it's a bit... it's a bit crumpled,
但我們可以很快地把它蒸出來，親愛的。
but we can steam that out in a jiffy, love.
-別擔心。 -不，看。
-Don't you worry. -No, look.
艾達：哦。
ADA: Oh.
哦親愛的。是的，不會出來的
Oh, dear. Yeah, that's not gonna come out
沒有好的，長時間的浸泡。
without a good, long soak.
我不確定緞子會不會喜歡那樣。
I'm not sure the satin's gonna like that.
你不是還有一個嗎？
Ain't you got another one?
那件可愛的藍色連衣裙呢？
What about that lovely blue dress?
- 在清潔工那裡。 -哦。
-It's at the cleaner's. -Oh.
我的天啊。
Oh, my God.
我就要死了。 [抽泣]
I'm going to die. [sobs]
好的。來吧，現在。這就夠了。
All right. Come on, now. That's enough.
沒有人願意聽到這個。
Nobody wants to hear that.
但你不明白。
But you don't understand.
幾乎所有科恩戈爾德先生的女孩都成為明星。
Nearly all Mr. Korngold's girls become stars.
這是我擺脫困境的機會
It's my chance to lift myself out of the rut
並最終被看到。 [抽泣]
and be seen at last. [sobs]
好吧，被人看見並不是一切，親愛的。
Well, being seen isn't everything, love.
這是給我的。
It is for me.
[帕梅拉哭泣]
[Pamela crying]
[帕梅拉抽泣]
[Pamela sniffling]
來吧。站起來。
Come on. Stand up.
這是你的幸運日。
It's your lucky day.
什麼？
What?
為什麼？
Why?
因為我想我可以幫助你。
'Cause I think I can help you.
你只是說你不能。
You just said you couldn't.
如果你不起來，我什麼都做不了。
I can't do anything if you don't get up.
正確的。
Right.
脫掉你的衣服。你可以藉我的衣服。
Take off your clothes. You can borrow my dress.
[笑]
[laughs]
不要荒謬。
Don't be ridiculous.
照我說的做，少廢話。
Just do as I say, and a bit less of your nonsense.
繼續，在屏幕後面。
Go on, behind the screen.
帕梅拉：哈里斯夫人？
PAMELA: Mrs. Harris?
哦。
Oh.
你看起來很可愛，鴨子。
You look lovely, ducks.
就憑票。
Just the ticket.
你的旅途怎麼樣？我應該問的。
How was your trip? I should've asked.
-你去哪兒？ -哦。
-Where did you go? -Oh.
巴黎。是的，那是...
Paris. Yeah, it was...
你說你只會離開一天。
You said you'd only be gone a day.
沒有你，一切都變得支離破碎。
Everything went to pieces without you.
這太神奇了。
It was magical.
我的意思是，你知道我有多整潔——通常情況下。
I mean, you know how tidy I am-- normally.
太浪漫了。
So romantic.
H 夫人
Mrs. H.
你這個黑馬。
You dark horse.
[笑]：哦。
[chuckles]: Oh.
[喇叭喇叭]
[horn honking]
天啊。就是他。
Oh, God. That's him.
哦。那麼，他知道該去哪裡嗎？
Oh. He knew where to come, then?
我知道你會救我，親愛的。
I knew you'd rescue me, darling.
你是我的仙女教母。
You're my fairy godmother.
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
[雷聲隆隆]
[thunder rumbling]
[車門關閉]
[car door closes]
艾達：你好。
ADA: Hello.
彭羅斯小姐？
Miss Penrose?
[吸鼻子，呻吟]哦。
[sniffs, groans] Oh.
[嘲笑]
[scoffs]
帕梅拉：親愛的 H 夫人，
PAMELA: Dear Mrs. H,
對不起，這件衣服，但請不要擔心。
Sorry about the dress, but please don't worry.
我很好。
I'm okay.
我在鏡子裡檢查我的口紅
I was checking my lipstick in the mirror
突然間，我火了起來。
when suddenly I went up in flames.
[尖叫]
[screams]
我可能已經燒焦了
I might have burnt to a crisp
如果沒有一位樂於助人的朋友來救我。
if a helpful friend hadn't come to my rescue.
[相機點擊]
[cameras clicking]
康戈爾德先生說我應該起訴。
Mr. Korngold says I should sue.
去媽媽家養傷。
Gone to my mum's to recover.
[按鍵叮噹聲]
[keys jingle]
[嘆氣]
[sighs]
[顫抖的呼吸]
[shuddering breath]
[海鷗叫聲]
[seagulls squawking]
[敲門]
[knocking at door]
[敲門聲繼續]
[knocking continues]
[玻璃破碎]
[glass shatters]
[門打開]
[door opens]
六：艾達？
VI: Ada?
你在那裡？
You there?
艾達：是的。
ADA: Yeah.
對不起，維。
Sorry, Vi.
[呻吟]
[groans]
【遠處的狗叫聲】
[dog barking in distance]
-[嘆氣] -VI：你放棄鬼了，女人？
-[sighs] -VI: You give up the ghost, woman?
你想把我們嚇死？
You want to scare us to death?
哦，好吧，阿奇？
Oh, all right, Archie?
呃，對不起你的門。
Uh, sorry about your door.
呃，她是，嗯……
Uh, she was, um...
最好的意圖和一切。
Best intentions and all.
我去拿些玻璃杯，是嗎？
I'll get some glass, yeah?
修好如新。
Fix it up good as new.
謝謝你。
Thank you.
好吧，沒有必要說一個字。
Well, there's no need to say a word.
你很有名。
You're famous.
至少你放棄一切去得到的衣服是。
At least the dress you gave up everything to go and get is.
你為什麼要把它給那個不好的女孩，嗯？
Why you give it to that no-good girl, eh?
你太軟了，這就是事實。
You're too soft, and that's the truth.
它必須被看到。
It had to be seen.
這是正確的。
It's only right.
哦，維。
Oh, Vi.
我從來沒有戴過它。
I never got to wear it.
一次都無。
Not even once.
哦，艾達，我的寶貝。
Oh, Ada, my darling.
我很抱歉，嗯？
I'm so sorry, eh?
嘿。
Hey.
我們不需要華麗的禮服。
We don't need no fancy dresses.
我們會在軍團舞會上甩掉我們的尾羽，
We'll go shake our tail feather down at the Legion Dance,
他們都會看著我們。
and they'll all be looking at us.
哦。
Aw.
哦，早上好，紐康先生。
Oh, morning, Mr. Newcombe.
享受你的假期嗎，哈里斯夫人？
Enjoy your holiday, Mrs. Harris?
非常感謝。
Very much, thank you.
錯過了你對這個地方的接觸。
Missed your touch about the place.
哦。 [輕笑]
Oh. [chuckles]
你還好嗎？
Are you quite all right?
今天不太像我自己。
Not quite meself today.
甚至不確定那是誰。
Not sure who that is, even.
有點生存危機。
Bit of an existential crisis.
巴黎會這樣對你。
Paris will do that to you.
振作起來，H 夫人。
Chin up, Mrs. H.
革命即將來臨。
The revolution is coming.
[口哨“馬賽曲”]
[whistles "La Marseillaise"]
[喘氣]
[gasps]
你讀過關於那個女孩的書嗎
Did you read about the girl
誰穿著迪奧禮服自焚？
who set fire to herself in a Dior gown?
[輕笑] 我想這是可怕的宣傳噱頭。
[chuckles] Ghastly publicity stunt, I suppose.
多麼浪費。
What a waste.
丹特夫人，請您接受我的通知好嗎？
Will you please accept my notice, Lady Dant?
我將要求您的帳戶完全和最終結算
I will require full and final settlement of your account
在這週結束之前。
by the end of the week.
你不能離開我。
You can't leave me.
可以把人當渣滓的日子已經結束了
Them days are over when you can treat people like scum
並期待忠誠的回報rn。
and expect loyalty in return.
是的。美好的一天，女士。
Yeah. Good day, milady.
你去吧。
There you go.
馬上就如雨一般。
Be right as rain in no time.
[敲門]
[knocking at door]
- 那是誰？ -[敲門聲繼續]
-Who's that, then? -[knocking continues]
艾達·哈里斯夫人？
Mrs. Ada Harris?
- 請在這裡簽名。 -哦。
-Sign here, please. -Oh.
-謝謝。 - 只是一個mo'。還有更多。
-Thank you. -Just a mo'. There's more.
更多的？
More?
[咕嚕聲]
[grunts]
[笑]：哦。
[laughs]: Oh.
你確定嗎？這不是我的生日。
Are you sure? It's not me birthday.
你是艾達哈里斯？
You are Ada Harris?
好吧，也不確定。
Well, not sure about that, either.
[都笑了]
[both laugh]
[嘆氣]
[sighs]
[喘氣]
[gasps]
COLBERT：Ch?艞re 哈里斯夫人，
COLBERT: Ch?艞re Madame Harris,
我們希望您返回倫敦的旅程是愉快的，
We hope your return journey to London was pleasant,
但我們對在社交頁面上看到的一張照片感到困擾。
but we were troubled by a photo we saw in the social pages.
我們馬上就知道了
We knew immediately that once again
你太客氣了。
you had been too kind.
安德烈？？？好像是垃圾之王
ANDRE??? It seems the rubbish king
從他的工人那裡偷東西。
was stealing from his workers.
喬治！喬治！
Georges! Georges!
安德烈？？？由於他的資產被沒收，
ANDRE??? Since his assets were seized,
阿瓦隆夫人未能參加她的最後一次試衣
Madame Avallon failed to attend her final fitting
或者為她的衣服買單。
or settle the bill for her dress.
卡雷？？？當然，我們保留了您的所有測量結果，
CARRE??? We kept all your measurements, of course,
並很快能夠為您改變它。
and were quickly able to alter it for you.
瑪格麗特：如果需要任何最後的調整，
MARGUERITE: If it needs any final adjustments,
我們知道你有能力自己做這些。
we know you have the skill to do these yourself.
[笑]
[laughs]
安德烈？？？我們都同意這是
ANDRE??? We all agreed it was
至少我們能做的。
the least we could do.
宣傳導致訂單量大增。
The publicity has resulted in a great increase in orders.
侯爵：你肯定會認出這些花朵
MARQUIS: You will no doubt recognize these blooms
作為瑪格麗特公主的喜悅。
as Princess Margaret's Delight.
我們希望你喜歡鮮花
We hope you enjoy the flowers
你會保留你的新衣服
and that you will keep your new dress
遠離明火。
well away from naked flames.
[安靜，模糊的喋喋不休]
[quiet, indistinct chatter]
娜塔莎：我們全心全意地把它寄給你
NATASHA: We send it to you with all our love
和我們最熱烈的感謝。
and our very warmest thanks.
DIOR：來自克里斯蒂安
DIOR: From Christian
和你在迪奧之家的所有朋友。
and all your friends at the House of Dior.
[輕輕喘氣]
[gasps softly]
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
[樂隊演奏歡快的曲子]
[band playing upbeat tune]
[安靜的喋喋不休，笑聲]
[quiet chatter, laughter]
迷人的。謝謝你。
Lovely. Thank you.
[模糊的喋喋不休]
[indistinct chatter]
G-很高興見到你。
G-Good to see you.
-回頭見。 -好的。
-See you later. -All right.
給你，親愛的。
There you go, love.
把它給你。
Get that down you.
-乾杯。 -乾杯。
-Cheers. -Cheers.
[人群竊竊私語]
[crowd murmuring]
謝謝你，維。
Thank you, Vi.
哦，艾達。
Oh, Ada.
[Vi 喘息，嘆氣]
[Vi gasps, sighs]
你沒事吧，阿奇？
You all right, Archie?
從來沒有更好的。
Never better.
S-對不起。
S-Sorry.
我只是...
I just...
什麼？
What?
你看起來不一樣。
You seem different.
嗯，這是高級時裝，你知道嗎？
Well, it's haute couture, you know?
是嗎，現在？
Is it, now?
-[輕笑] -知道嗎？
-[chuckles] -Know what?
這不是連衣裙。我的意思是，它很可愛，而且，
It's not the frock. I mean, it's lovely and all,
但是，呃...
but, uh...
不，是你。
no, it's you.
你...
You...
你只是美麗。
You're just beautiful.
謝謝你，阿奇。
Thank you, Archie.
你真好歐。
That's very nice of you.
不，我是說，你一直都很漂亮。
No, I mean, you've always been beautiful.
從內到外。
Inside and out.
只是，有事...
Just, there's something...
我不知道，比如，新的火花之類的。
I don't know, like, a new spark or something.
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
一個je ne sais quoi？
A je ne sais quoi?
- 那就是那個傢伙。 -[笑]
-That'll be the fella. -[laughs]
我欠你一支舞，不是嗎？
I owe you a dance, don't I?
我想你會的。
I think you do.
我想認領那支舞
I'd like to claim that dance
和房間裡最可愛的女孩在一起。
with the loveliest girl in the room.
這是你的幸運日。
It's your lucky day.
[笑]：哦。
[chuckles]: Oh.
好的。
All right.
[輕笑]
[chuckles]
我們所有人都有希望。
There is hope for us all.
[笑]
[laughing]
[音樂消失]
[music fades]